<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Luke&#39;s Statistics Blog</title>
    <link>https://lucarep.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Luke&#39;s Statistics Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2021 Luca Repechini</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lucarep.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>MY FIRST POST</title>
      <link>https://lucarep.github.io/post/hello/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lucarep.github.io/post/hello/</guid>
      <description>Hello there, this is my first blog post. I don&amp;rsquo;t have much to say about this, but I invite you to stay tuned because in the coming days will come out many articles.
 Also, there will be two categories of post here:
 Researches about theory (R) Applications / Practice (A)  So, keep in mind which one of the two letters the post contains, because it is to specify at a glance its type.</description>
      <content>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello there, this is my first blog post. I don&amp;rsquo;t have much to say about this, but I invite you to &lt;strong&gt;stay tuned&lt;/strong&gt; because in the coming days will come out many articles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, there will be two categories of post here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Researches about theory (&lt;strong&gt;R&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Applications / Practice (&lt;strong&gt;A&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, keep in mind which one of the two letters the post contains, because it is to specify at a glance its type.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1_R&lt;/strong&gt; its a possible title of a post about Research&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1_A&lt;/strong&gt; its a possible title of a post about Applications / Practice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://lucarep.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lucarep.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi there if you want to know more about me and the blog, you are in the right place. My name is Luca, I&amp;rsquo;m a computer engineer and currently a CyberSecurity student at la Sapienza, previously i was a computer engineering student also at la Sapienza. This blog is hosted with GitHub pages and made with Hugo a framework for building websites. The main topic of the blog is statistics (as you can imagine from the title of the website), here i will post all my assigned homework, I hope you will find the research posted here useful.</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;hi-there&#34;&gt;Hi there&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;if-you-want-to-know-more-about-me-and-the-blog-you-are-in-the-right-place&#34;&gt;if you want to know more about me and the blog, you are in the right place.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My name is Luca, I&amp;rsquo;m a computer engineer and currently a CyberSecurity student at la Sapienza, previously i was a computer engineering student also at la Sapienza. This blog is hosted with GitHub pages and made with Hugo a framework for building websites. The main topic of the blog is statistics (as you can imagine from the title of the website), here i will post all my assigned homework, I hope you will find the research posted here useful. Also, if you&amp;rsquo;re interested about my other past projects, I invite you to check out my &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/lucarep&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
