<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Research on Luke&#39;s Statistics Blog</title>
    <link>https://lucarep.github.io/tags/research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Research on Luke&#39;s Statistics Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2021 Luca Repechini</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lucarep.github.io/tags/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>9_RA</title>
      <link>https://lucarep.github.io/homework9/9_ra/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lucarep.github.io/homework9/9_ra/</guid>
      <description>Table of contents
 INTRO NORMAL DISTRIBUTION LOG-NORMAL DISTRIBUTION CHI-SQUARED DISTRIBUTION RATIO BETWEEN TWO CHI-SQUARED DISTRIBUTIONS - Credits  INTRO In the application made in post 13_A, we saw numerous distributions, let&amp;rsquo;s now see in more detail a description of each.
NORMAL DISTRIBUTION We&amp;rsquo;ve previously discussed normal distribution and its history in a blog post. However, in short to recap, it is a continuous probability distribution that is often used as a first approximation to describe real-valued random variables that tend to concentrate around a single mean value</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Table of contents&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#intro&#34;&gt;INTRO&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#normal-distribution&#34;&gt;NORMAL DISTRIBUTION&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#log-normal-distribution&#34;&gt;LOG-NORMAL DISTRIBUTION&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#chi-squared-distribution&#34;&gt;CHI-SQUARED DISTRIBUTION&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#ratio-between-two-chi-squared-distributions&#34;&gt;RATIO BETWEEN TWO CHI-SQUARED DISTRIBUTIONS&lt;/a&gt;
- &lt;a href=&#34;#credits&#34;&gt;Credits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;INTRO&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the application made in post 13_A, we saw numerous distributions, let&amp;rsquo;s now see in more detail a description of each.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;normal-distribution&#34;&gt;NORMAL DISTRIBUTION&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve previously discussed normal distribution and its history in a blog post. However, in short to recap, it is a continuous probability distribution that is often used as a first approximation to describe real-valued random variables that tend to concentrate around a single mean value&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;log-normal-distribution&#34;&gt;LOG-NORMAL DISTRIBUTION&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lognormal distribution plays an important role in probabilistic design because negative values of engineering phenomena are sometimes physically impossible. Typical uses of lognormal distribution are found in descriptions of fatigue failure, failure rates, and other phenomena involving a large range of data. The lognormal distribution of a random variable X with expected value μX and standard deviation σX is denoted LN(μX,σX) and is defined as:
$$ fx(x) = \frac{2}{\sqrt{2\pi}\sigma}e^{-\frac{1}{2}(\frac{ln(x) - \sigma}{\sigma})^2}$$
in which fX(x) is the PDF of the random variable X.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;chi-squared-distribution&#34;&gt;CHI-SQUARED DISTRIBUTION&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A chi-square distribution is a continuous distribution with  degrees of freedom. It is used to describe the distribution of a sum of squared random variables. It is also used to test the goodness of fit of a distribution of data, whether data series are independent, and for estimating confidences surrounding variance and standard deviation for a random variable from a normal distribution. Additionally, chi-square distribution is a special case of the gamma distribution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;ratio-between-two-chi-squared-distributions&#34;&gt;RATIO BETWEEN TWO CHI-SQUARED DISTRIBUTIONS&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last distribution we saw is a ratio between two chi-squared distributions, which can also be seen as an absolutely continuous probability distribution called beta prime distribution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&#34;credits&#34;&gt;Credits&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to thank and mention some resources that I found particularly helpful in the writing of this post:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Normal_distribution&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Normal_distribution&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sciencedirect.com/topics/engineering/lognormal-distribution&#34;&gt;https://www.sciencedirect.com/topics/engineering/lognormal-distribution&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sciencedirect.com/topics/mathematics/chi-square-distribution&#34;&gt;https://www.sciencedirect.com/topics/mathematics/chi-square-distribution&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Beta_prime_distribution&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Beta_prime_distribution&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>13_R</title>
      <link>https://lucarep.github.io/homework9/13_r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lucarep.github.io/homework9/13_r/</guid>
      <description>INTRO We have already seen in post 12_R, the definition of Brownian motion (also called Wiener process), however as the ancient Romans also said:
 &amp;ldquo;Repetita iuvant&amp;rdquo;
 So, in short, we can say that the Brownian motion is a standard process (one-dimensional) and stochastic, indexed with non-negative real numbers denoted by t.
BROWNIAN MOTION AS A LIMIT FOR RANDOM WALK One of several reasons, which makes the Brownian motion so important in probability theory is that it represents, in a sense, a limit for a rescaled random walk.</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;INTRO&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have already seen in post 12_R, the definition of Brownian motion (also called Wiener process), however as the ancient Romans also said:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Repetita iuvant&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, in short, we can say that the Brownian motion is a standard process (one-dimensional) and stochastic, indexed with non-negative real numbers denoted by t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;brownian-motion-as-a-limit-for-random-walk&#34;&gt;BROWNIAN MOTION AS A LIMIT FOR RANDOM WALK&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of several reasons, which makes the Brownian motion so important in probability theory is that it represents, in a sense, a limit for a rescaled random walk.
Let:
$$\epsilon_{1},\epsilon_{2}&amp;hellip;$$
Be a sequence of random variables, independent and identically distributed, with mean equal to 0 and variance equal to 1.
For each:
$$n \geq 1$$
You define a continuos-time stochastic process by:
$$W_{n}(t) = \frac{1}{\sqrt{n}}\sum_{1 \leq j \leq |nt|} \epsilon_{j}$$
This is a random step function with jumps of size:
$$[\frac{1}{\sqrt{n}},-\frac{1}{\sqrt{n}}]$$
at times:
$$\frac{k}{n}$$
Where:
$$k \in Z$$
Since the random variables are independent, the increments are independent. Moreover for large *n* the distribution of:
$$W_{n}(t + s) - W_{n}(s)$$
is close to the Normal(0,t), by the Central limit theorem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;why-is-it-important&#34;&gt;WHY IS IT IMPORTANT?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, it explains, why the Wiener process arises so commonly in nature. Many stochastic process behave, at least for long stretches of time, like random walks with small but frequent jumps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The argument above suggests that such processes will look, at least approximately, and on the appropriate time scale, like Brownian motion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;second, it suggests that many important “statistics” of the random walk will have limiiting distributions, and that the limiting distributions will be the distributions of the corresponding statistics of Brownian motion. The simplest instance of this principle is the central limit theorem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;extension-of-the-clt-the-donskers-theorem&#34;&gt;EXTENSION OF THE CLT, THE DONSKER&amp;rsquo;S THEOREM&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In its modern form, Donsker&amp;rsquo;s invariance principle states that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As random variables taking values in the Skorokhod space D [0,1] (The set of all càdlàg functions from E to M is often denoted by D(E,M) and is called Skorokhod space), the random function W(n) converges in distribution to a standard Brownian motion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&#34;credits&#34;&gt;Credits&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to thank and mention some resources that I found particularly helpful in the writing of this post:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://galton.uchicago.edu/~lalley/Courses/313/BrownianMotionCurrent.pdf&#34;&gt;https://galton.uchicago.edu/~lalley/Courses/313/BrownianMotionCurrent.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Donsker%27s_theorem&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Donsker%27s_theorem&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>12_R : ATOMS EXISTS, HERE&#39;S WHY</title>
      <link>https://lucarep.github.io/homework9/12_r/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lucarep.github.io/homework9/12_r/</guid>
      <description>Table of contents
 INTRO THE KINETIC THEORY OF MATTER EINSTEIN AND SEALS BROWNIAN MOTION IN STATISTICS WHY IT IS IMPORTANT - Credits  INTRO Brownian Motion is useful among other things to confirm a very important thing, the existence of atoms. Imagine you are in a dark room the air is still and bright lights are coming out of the window, you will have noticed that there are dust particles floating in the air.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Table of contents&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#intro&#34;&gt;INTRO&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#the-kinetic-theory-of-matter&#34;&gt;THE KINETIC THEORY OF MATTER&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#einstein-and-seals&#34;&gt;EINSTEIN AND SEALS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#brownian-motion-in-statistics&#34;&gt;BROWNIAN MOTION IN STATISTICS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#why-it-is-important&#34;&gt;WHY IT IS IMPORTANT&lt;/a&gt;
- &lt;a href=&#34;#credits&#34;&gt;Credits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;INTRO&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brownian Motion is useful among other things to confirm a very important thing, the existence of atoms. Imagine you are in a dark room the air is still and bright lights are coming out of the window, you will have noticed that there are dust particles floating in the air. These particles are very interesting, because they move randomly, if you noticed they don&amp;rsquo;t all go down, but they move in all directions, the reason for this is that they are surrounded by a gas that obviously you can&amp;rsquo;t see. You can imagine these dust particles as so many billiard balls being hit. The first person to observe this effect was Robert Brown. 
&lt;img src=&#34;https://lucarep.github.io/img/pool.gif&#34; alt=&#34;pool&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-kinetic-theory-of-matter&#34;&gt;THE KINETIC THEORY OF MATTER&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brown however had a problem, he had observed this phenomenon, understanding that it was not related to biology, but rather to physics, however he could not give an answer as to why it occurred. The answer came a century later with the Kinetic Thoery of Matter, thanks to scientists such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;J.C. Maxwell&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;L. Boltzmann&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;R.J.E Clausius
Who stated that:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;All matter consists of atoms or molecules constantly in motion&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;einstein-and-seals&#34;&gt;EINSTEIN AND SEALS&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Einstein, in 1905 explained this motion in detail, accurately predicting the random motions of particles that can be observed directly under a microscope. In 1908, he published a second paper on Brownian motion adding details over the first, including a way to test his theory.  This was crucial, because, thanks to this scientists could prove the existence of atoms and molecules. Also, he derived the size of atoms based on how brownian particles move, in other words it was like :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Guessing the size of a seal, by observing how icebergs move near it&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://lucarep.github.io/img/seal.gif&#34; alt=&#34;seal&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;brownian-motion-in-statistics&#34;&gt;BROWNIAN MOTION IN STATISTICS&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brownian motion in statistics is a Levy process, from which we derive certain properties such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stationary increments (i.e. increments that depend only on delta)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Independent increments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Continuity in probability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Increments has the N(0,delta(t)) distribution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;X0 = 0&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;why-it-is-important&#34;&gt;WHY IT IS IMPORTANT&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, we can see Brownian motion somewhat as the convergence for the Central Limit Theorem of random variables to the Normal distribution, but we will explore this in more detail in the next post. It is also important in real-world scenarios, such as finance, in which it can simulate market fluctuations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&#34;credits&#34;&gt;Credits&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to thank and mention some resources that I found particularly helpful in the writing of this post:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4m5JnJBq2AU&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4m5JnJBq2AU&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=i7tQLjGZR0A&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=i7tQLjGZR0A&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tommaso Gastaldi&amp;rsquo;s lecture (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=i7tQLjGZR0A&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=i7tQLjGZR0A&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>8_RA: POISSON AND DITTO</title>
      <link>https://lucarep.github.io/homework8/8_ra/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lucarep.github.io/homework8/8_ra/</guid>
      <description>Table of contents
 INTRO POISSON CAN BE NORMAL POISSON CAN BE UNIFORM POISSON CAN BE EXPONENTIAL CONCLUSIONS  INTRO If Poisson&amp;rsquo;s distribution were lumped in with a Pokemon, this would probably be&amp;hellip; Ditto. The reason why, for those unfamiliar with Games Freak&amp;rsquo;s popular franchise is relatively simple. This pokemon is peculiar, because it can take on the appearance of all others. In a certain way this also applies to the distribution of Poisson, let&amp;rsquo;s see why.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Table of contents&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#intro&#34;&gt;INTRO&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#poisson-can-be-normal&#34;&gt;POISSON CAN BE NORMAL&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#poisson-can-be-uniform&#34;&gt;POISSON CAN BE UNIFORM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#poisson-can-be-exponential&#34;&gt;POISSON CAN BE EXPONENTIAL&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#conclusions&#34;&gt;CONCLUSIONS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;INTRO&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If Poisson&amp;rsquo;s distribution were lumped in with a Pokemon, this would probably be&amp;hellip; Ditto.
&lt;img src=&#34;https://lucarep.github.io/img/ditto.gif&#34; alt=&#34;ditto&#34;&gt;
The reason why, for those unfamiliar with Games Freak&amp;rsquo;s popular franchise is relatively simple. This pokemon is peculiar, because it can take on the appearance of all others. In a certain way this also applies to the distribution of Poisson, let&amp;rsquo;s see why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;poisson-can-be-normal&#34;&gt;POISSON CAN BE NORMAL&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we notice the histograms of the application shown in post 11_A, we can see that as n increases, the distribution tends to the normal distribution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;poisson-can-be-uniform&#34;&gt;POISSON CAN BE UNIFORM&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we take in analysis another histogram of the application, that is the one representing the distribution of the distance of the individual jumps from the origin, what we can observe, is that the distribution in question is referable to a uniform distribution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;poisson-can-be-exponential&#34;&gt;POISSON CAN BE EXPONENTIAL&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, the last case, let&amp;rsquo;s look at the histogram representing the distance between two consecutive jumps. What we observe is an exponential trend, then an exponential distribution, however the reason is easily explained. The jumps represent successes, the possibility of having a success in a short period compared to the previous one is relatively higher than having one in a very long period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;conclusions&#34;&gt;CONCLUSIONS&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What we have learned from this analysis, is that the dsitribution of Poisson can take on various guises depending on what you observe, do not you find that after all it is a bit similar to Ditto?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10_R</title>
      <link>https://lucarep.github.io/homework8/10_r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lucarep.github.io/homework8/10_r/</guid>
      <description>Table of contents
 INTRO ALL VALUES ARE IMPORTANT, BUT SOME SOME VALUES ARE MORE IMPORTANT THAN OTHERS UNIFORM DISTRIBUTION AN EXAMPLE PROBABILITY DENSITY - Credits  INTRO In statistics, the kth order statistic of a statistical sample is equal to its kth-smallest value. Together with rank statistics, order statistics are among the most fundamental tools in non-parametric statistics and inference.
ALL VALUES ARE IMPORTANT, BUT SOME SOME VALUES ARE MORE IMPORTANT THAN OTHERS Yes, I&amp;rsquo;m not quoting George Orwell at random, the reason is that in order statistics, there are much more important numbers than others within the dataset.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Table of contents&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#intro&#34;&gt;INTRO&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#all-values-are-important-but-some-some-values-are-more-important-than-others&#34;&gt;ALL VALUES ARE IMPORTANT, BUT SOME SOME VALUES ARE MORE IMPORTANT THAN OTHERS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#uniform-distribution&#34;&gt;UNIFORM DISTRIBUTION&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#an-example&#34;&gt;AN EXAMPLE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#probability-density&#34;&gt;PROBABILITY DENSITY&lt;/a&gt;
- &lt;a href=&#34;#credits&#34;&gt;Credits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;INTRO&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In statistics, the kth order statistic of a statistical sample is equal to its kth-smallest value. Together with rank statistics, order statistics are among the most fundamental tools in non-parametric statistics and inference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;all-values-are-important-but-some-some-values-are-more-important-than-others&#34;&gt;ALL VALUES ARE IMPORTANT, BUT SOME SOME VALUES ARE MORE IMPORTANT THAN OTHERS&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, I&amp;rsquo;m not quoting George Orwell at random, the reason is that in order statistics, there are much more important numbers than others within the dataset. 
These values are the minimum, the maximum, the one in the middle(which in this case also represents the median)and other quantiles of the sample.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;uniform-distribution&#34;&gt;UNIFORM DISTRIBUTION&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When using probability theory to analyze order statistics of random samples from a continuous distribution, the cumulative distribution function is used to reduce the analysis to the case of order statistics of the uniform distribution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;an-example&#34;&gt;AN EXAMPLE&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The order statistic as I see it is easier to understand with an example, so let&amp;rsquo;s look at one.
Imagine that you have a sample consisting of four elements, and suppose that these are their measured values:
$$6,9,3,8$$
Well, what we need to do now to get an order statistic, is trivially put them in order. 
&lt;img src=&#34;https://lucarep.github.io/img/annoyed.gif&#34; alt=&#34;annoyed&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What we get then is:
$$3,6,8,9$$
The order statistic is then denoted as:
$$x_{(1)} = 3, x_{(2)} = 6, x_{(3)} = 8, x_{(4)} = 9$$
Where, the first order statistic (or smallest order statistic) is always the minimum of the sample:
$$X_{(1)} = min(X_{1},&amp;hellip;,X_{n}) $$
Similarly, for a sample of size n, the nth order statistic (or largest order statistic) is the maximum, that is:
$$X_{(n)} = max(X_{1},&amp;hellip;,X_{n}) $$
Very interesting, is also the sample range defined as the difference between the maximum and minimum. It is a function of the order statistics:
$$\text{Range}(X_{1},&amp;hellip;,X_{n}) = X_{(n)} - X_{(1)}$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;probability-density&#34;&gt;PROBABILITY DENSITY&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The PDF, by definition, for X(k) is:
$$\lim_{dx \to 0} \frac{p(X_{(1)}\in(x,x + dx))}{dx}$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&#34;credits&#34;&gt;Credits&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to thank and mention some resources that I found particularly helpful in the writing of this post:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Order_statistic&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Order_statistic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>11_R</title>
      <link>https://lucarep.github.io/homework8/11_r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lucarep.github.io/homework8/11_r/</guid>
      <description>Table of contents
 DEFINITION OF RANKING RANKING IN STATISTICS AN EXAMPLE RANK CORRELATION KENDALL RANK CORRELATION SPEARMAN RANK CORRELATION WHERE WE CAN USE IT? - Credits  DEFINITION OF RANKING A ranking is a relationship between a set of items such that, for any two items, the first is either ‘ranked higher than’, ‘ranked lower than’ or ‘ranked equal to’ the second. In mathematics, this is known as a weak order or total preorder of objects.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Table of contents&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#definition-of-ranking&#34;&gt;DEFINITION OF RANKING&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#ranking-in-statistics&#34;&gt;RANKING IN STATISTICS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#an-example&#34;&gt;AN EXAMPLE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#rank-correlation&#34;&gt;RANK CORRELATION&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#kendall-rank-correlation&#34;&gt;KENDALL RANK CORRELATION&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#spearman-rank-correlation&#34;&gt;SPEARMAN RANK CORRELATION&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#where-we-can-use-it&#34;&gt;WHERE WE CAN USE IT?&lt;/a&gt;
- &lt;a href=&#34;#credits&#34;&gt;Credits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;definition-of-ranking&#34;&gt;DEFINITION OF RANKING&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A ranking is a relationship between a set of items such that, for any two items, the first is either ‘ranked higher than’, ‘ranked lower than’ or ‘ranked equal to’ the second. 
&lt;img src=&#34;https://lucarep.github.io/img/rank.gif&#34; alt=&#34;rank&#34;&gt;
In mathematics, this is known as a weak order or total preorder of objects. It is not necessarily a total order of objects because two different objects can have the same ranking. The rankings themselves are totally ordered. For example, materials are totally preordered by hardness, while degrees of hardness are totally ordered. If two items are the same in rank it is considered a tie.
There are several ways to solve a tie, one of them is to average all rankings of equal values that generate one of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;ranking-in-statistics&#34;&gt;RANKING IN STATISTICS&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In statistics, ranking is the data transformation in which numerical or ordinal values are replaced by their rank when the data are sorted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;an-example&#34;&gt;AN EXAMPLE&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine that you have a sample consisting of four elements, and suppose that these are their measured values:
$$ 3.4, 5.1, 2.6, 7.3$$
The ranks of those numbers would be:
$$ 2,3,1,4 $$
the reason is that 3.4 is the second smallest value in the sample, 5.1 the third and so on.
But ranks does not apply only to numbers, imagine that we have the ordinal data:
$$\text{hot},\text{cold},\text{warm}$$
We can rank them as:
$$3,1,2$$
In these examples, the ranks are assigned to values in ascending order. (In some other cases, descending ranks are used.) Ranks are related to the indexed list of order statistics (which we have already discussed in the previous post).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;rank-correlation&#34;&gt;RANK CORRELATION&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A rank correlation is any of several statistics that measure an ordinal association(the relationship between rankings of different ordinal variables or different rankings of the same variable). A rank correlation coefficient measures the degree of similarity between two rankings, and can be used to assess the significance of the relation between them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;kendall-rank-correlation&#34;&gt;KENDALL RANK CORRELATION&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kendall rank correlation is a non-parametric test that measures the strength of dependence between two variables.  If we consider two samples, a and b, where each sample size is n, we know that the total number of pairings with a b is n(n-1)/2.  The following formula is used to calculate the value of Kendall rank correlation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$$ \tau = \frac{n_{c} - n_{d}}{\frac{1}{2}n(n - 1)}$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$$ n_{c} = \text{number of concordant}$$
$$ n_{d} = \text{number of discordant}$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other words:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Concordant: Ordered in the same way&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discordant: Ordered differently&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;spearman-rank-correlation&#34;&gt;SPEARMAN RANK CORRELATION&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spearman rank correlation is a non-parametric test that is used to measure the degree of association between two variables.  The Spearman rank correlation test does not carry any assumptions about the distribution of the data and is the appropriate correlation analysis when the variables are measured on a scale that is at least ordinal.
The following formula is used to calculate the Spearman rank correlation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$$ \rho = 1 - \frac{\sum d_{i}^2}{n(n^{2} - 1)}$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$$ \rho = \text{Spearman rank correlation}$$
$$ d_{i} = \text{the difference between the ranks of corresponding variables}$$
$$n = \text{number of observations}$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;where-we-can-use-it&#34;&gt;WHERE WE CAN USE IT?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can use it to answer questions like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is there a statistically significant relationship between participants’ level of education (high school, bachelor’s, or graduate degree) and their starting salary?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is there a statistically significant relationship between horse’s finishing position a race and horse’s age?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&#34;credits&#34;&gt;Credits&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to thank and mention some resources that I found particularly helpful in the writing of this post:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ranking&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ranking&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.statisticssolutions.com/free-resources/directory-of-statistical-analyses/correlation-pearson-kendall-spearman/&#34;&gt;https://www.statisticssolutions.com/free-resources/directory-of-statistical-analyses/correlation-pearson-kendall-spearman/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>9_R : HISTORY OF THE NORMAL DISTRIBUTION</title>
      <link>https://lucarep.github.io/homework7/9_r/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lucarep.github.io/homework7/9_r/</guid>
      <description>Table of contents
 BINOMIAL DISTRIBUTION DE MOIVRE AND GAMBLERS THE NORMAL CURVE GAUSS AND THE NORMAL DISTRIBUTION LAPLACE AND THE CENTRAL LIMIT THEOREM HUMANS AFTER ALL - Credits  BINOMIAL DISTRIBUTION Our story begins here, with the binomial distribution, 0 and 1 have not only played an important role in the history of computer science, but, also in the history of probability and statistics. We know about this distribution, which is useful for giving us answers to questions like this:</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Table of contents&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#binomial-distribution&#34;&gt;BINOMIAL DISTRIBUTION&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#de-moivre-and-gamblers&#34;&gt;DE MOIVRE AND GAMBLERS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#the-normal-curve&#34;&gt;THE NORMAL CURVE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#gauss-and-the-normal-distribution&#34;&gt;GAUSS AND THE NORMAL DISTRIBUTION&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#laplace-and-the-central-limit-theorem&#34;&gt;LAPLACE AND THE CENTRAL LIMIT THEOREM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#humans-after-all&#34;&gt;HUMANS AFTER ALL&lt;/a&gt;
- &lt;a href=&#34;#credits&#34;&gt;Credits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;binomial-distribution&#34;&gt;BINOMIAL DISTRIBUTION&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our story begins here, with the binomial distribution, 0 and 1 have not only played an important role in the history of computer science, but, also in the history of probability and statistics. We know about this distribution, which is useful for giving us answers to questions like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a flair coin is flipped 100 times, what is the probability of getting 60 or more heads?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this then there is a formula:
$$ P(X) = \frac{N!}{x!(N - x)!}\pi^{x}(1 - \pi)^{N - x} $$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More specifically:
$$P(60) + P(61) + P(62) &amp;hellip; P(N)$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is however a big problem with this formula, before the advent of computers (and even today), calculating factorial numbers was very expensive, so a better formula was needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;de-moivre-and-gamblers&#34;&gt;DE MOIVRE AND GAMBLERS&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abraham de Moivre, among other things was a consulant to gamblers, what he noticed was that as the number of events increased, the distribution could be approximated to a smooth curve. de Moivre understood then, that if he had found the formula for this curve, he would have been able to find the probability for problems like the one described just now, in much less time. This, therefore, is exactly what he did and that curve, today is called normal curve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-normal-curve&#34;&gt;THE NORMAL CURVE&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many natural phenomena are approximated this way:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Astronomical observations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mathematics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the first applications of the curve, was to remedy errors of approximations made in astronomical observations, errors were present because of imperfect instruments and imperfect people. Galileo Galilei in the seventeenth century, noted that these errors were symmetrical, in addition to the fact that small errors were more frequent than large errors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;gauss-and-the-normal-distribution&#34;&gt;GAUSS AND THE NORMAL DISTRIBUTION&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gauss was the first to discover the normal distribution, The general form of its probability density function is:
$$ f(x) = \frac{1}{\sigma\sqrt{2\pi}}e^{-\frac{1}{2}(\frac{x - \mu}{\sigma})^{2}}$$
The parameter: $$\mu$$  is the mean or expectation of the distribution (and also its median and mode), while the parameter: $$\sigma$$  is its standard deviation. The variance of the distribution is: $$\sigma^2$$ A random variable with a Gaussian distribution is said to be normally distributed, and is called a normal deviate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;laplace-and-the-central-limit-theorem&#34;&gt;LAPLACE AND THE CENTRAL LIMIT THEOREM&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same distribution was discovered by Laplace in 1778. From here he derived the central limit theorem (which we discussed in some previous posts), what he proved, is that even if a distribution is not normal, the sample mean, can be approximated as such.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;humans-after-all&#34;&gt;HUMANS AFTER ALL&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quètelet was the first to apply the normal distribution to human characteristics; in fact, he noted that some traits such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;height&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;weight&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;strength
were normally distributed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&#34;credits&#34;&gt;Credits&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to thank and mention some resources that I found particularly helpful in the writing of this post:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BXof869EC68&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BXof869EC68&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Normal_distribution&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Normal_distribution&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>7_RA : MONKEYS AND SHAKESPEARE</title>
      <link>https://lucarep.github.io/homework7/7_ra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lucarep.github.io/homework7/7_ra/</guid>
      <description>Table of contents
 INTRO WHAT IS RANDOM WALK? WHERE WE CAN FIND IT IN REAL LIFE? HOW WE CAN UNDERSTAND IT BETTER WITH A SIMPLE EXAMPLE ROOT-MEAN-SQUARE DISTANCE LET&amp;rsquo;S TALK ABOUT THE MONKEYS&amp;hellip; DONSKER&amp;rsquo;S INVARIANCE PRINCIPLE - Credits  INTRO We can begin our journey in this post, with the following question:
 What do Shakespeare and monkeys have in common?
 We will answer this question later, for now let&amp;rsquo;s just introduce the concept of random walk.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Table of contents&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#intro&#34;&gt;INTRO&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#what-is-random-walk&#34;&gt;WHAT IS RANDOM WALK?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#where-we-can-find-it-in-real-life&#34;&gt;WHERE WE CAN FIND IT IN REAL LIFE?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#how-we-can-understand-it-better-with-a-simple-example&#34;&gt;HOW WE CAN UNDERSTAND IT BETTER WITH A SIMPLE EXAMPLE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#root-mean-square-distance&#34;&gt;ROOT-MEAN-SQUARE DISTANCE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#lets-talk-about-the-monkeys&#34;&gt;LET&amp;rsquo;S TALK ABOUT THE MONKEYS&amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#donskers-invariance-principle&#34;&gt;DONSKER&amp;rsquo;S INVARIANCE PRINCIPLE&lt;/a&gt;
- &lt;a href=&#34;#credits&#34;&gt;Credits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;INTRO&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can begin our journey in this post, with the following question:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do Shakespeare and monkeys have in common?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will answer this question later, for now let&amp;rsquo;s just introduce the concept of random walk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-is-random-walk&#34;&gt;WHAT IS RANDOM WALK?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A random walk refers to any process in which there is no observable pattern or trend; that is, where the movements of an object, or the values taken by a certain variable, are completely random.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;where-we-can-find-it-in-real-life&#34;&gt;WHERE WE CAN FIND IT IN REAL LIFE?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Certain real-life scenarios that could be modeled as random walks could be:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The path traced by a molecule as it moves through a liquid or a gas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The price of a stock as it moves up and down&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The financial status of a gambler at the roulette wheel in Las Vegas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-we-can-understand-it-better-with-a-simple-example&#34;&gt;HOW WE CAN UNDERSTAND IT BETTER WITH A SIMPLE EXAMPLE&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To illustrate the concept of random walk a bit further, let’s look at the simplest random walk: a random walk along on the integer number line. Now, we&amp;rsquo;re going to do a little experiment. Imagine you are standing on zero. You flip a fair coin, and if it lands on heads, you will take one step (one unit) to the right. However, if the coin lands tails, you will take one step to the left, again, one unit. Therefore, with each coin toss there is a 50% chance you will move to the right, and a 50% chance you move to the left. Let&amp;rsquo;s imagine we flipped the coin 10 times and got:
$$HHHTHHTTTT$$
This would generate the following random walk:
$$right, right, right, left, right, right, left, left, left, left$$
We can illustrate it as follows:
&lt;img src=&#34;https://lucarep.github.io/img/ranndwalk.png&#34; alt=&#34;ranwalk&#34;&gt;
In this case, we happen to end up back where we started: at zero. This random walk happened to work out that way, but it need not have dropped us off where we began. However, it turns out that because the probabilities of moving right or left are equal, we have a symmetrical random walk, where we will, on average, end up back where we started, at zero.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;root-mean-square-distance&#34;&gt;ROOT-MEAN-SQUARE DISTANCE&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has been found empirically that for a random walk after n steps, we will find ourselves approximately:
$$\sqrt{n}$$ 
away from the initial zero point.
So, for example, if we have 49,100,256 steps we can expect to be this distance far away from zero:
$$ 7,10,16 $$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;lets-talk-about-the-monkeys&#34;&gt;LET&amp;rsquo;S TALK ABOUT THE MONKEYS&amp;hellip;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the discussion on root-mean-square distance, we see that as n gets larger, we expect to get further and further from the origin. In fact, for an infinite number of random walks with an infinitely large number of steps, we will end up visiting every number on the number line.
So, this in practice mean that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given an ininite number of monkeys, typewriters and time, some of those apes will outdo Shakespeare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://lucarep.github.io/img/monkeys.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Monkeys&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;donskers-invariance-principle&#34;&gt;DONSKER&amp;rsquo;S INVARIANCE PRINCIPLE&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let:
$$\xi_{1},&amp;hellip;,\xi_{n}$$
be i.i.d random variables with mean 0 and variance:
$$\sigma^{2}$$
Then we have for X:
$$(X_{t}^{(n)},t \geq 0) \implies (B_{t},t \geq 0)$$
In C, where:
$$ (B_{t},t \geq 0) $$
Is a standard Brownian motion.
This theorem, was first given by Monroe Donsker in (1951). In the paper, he gave the motivation for studying such an invariance principle. Here, you can see an illustration the theorem at work for the simple random walk case. What this plot really shows is the convergence of our rescaled random walk to a Brownian motion sample path.
&lt;img src=&#34;https://lucarep.github.io/img/donsker.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Donsker&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&#34;credits&#34;&gt;Credits&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to thank and mention some resources that I found particularly helpful in the writing of this post:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://magoosh.com/statistics/what-is-random-walk-theory/&#34;&gt;https://magoosh.com/statistics/what-is-random-walk-theory/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://people.cam.cornell.edu/amt269/DonskerSimulate.html&#34;&gt;https://people.cam.cornell.edu/amt269/DonskerSimulate.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6_RA</title>
      <link>https://lucarep.github.io/homework6/6_ra/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lucarep.github.io/homework6/6_ra/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents
 THE RUNNING MEDIAN JAVA ALGORITHM  THE RUNNING MEDIAN As we have already seen in the previous dedicated article,the median of a set of integers is the midpoint value of the data set for which an equal number of integers are less than and greater than the value.
 If we keep each number in a sorted sequence then cost of single entry is O(n) and finding median is O(n).</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#the-running-median&#34;&gt;THE RUNNING MEDIAN&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#java-algorithm&#34;&gt;JAVA ALGORITHM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-running-median&#34;&gt;THE RUNNING MEDIAN&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we have already seen in the previous dedicated article,the median of a set of integers is the midpoint value of the data set for which an equal number of integers are less than and greater than the value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If we keep each number in a sorted sequence then cost of single entry is O(n) and finding median is O(n).
A slight modification can be done by keeping the middle pointer and adjusting it based on the insertion on its left side and right side. In that case finding median after insertion is O(1). But the overall cost for finding median still remains O(n) as insertion in sorted sequence is necessary after each number is entered.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We can keep two heaps which divides the entered number in two almost equal halves. Half of the number would be greater than the median and the rest would be lesser. The upper half will be maintained in a min heap and the lower half will be maintained in a max heap. In this arrangement we can find out in O(1) time whether a new number would go to the upper half or lower half. All we need to do is to compare the new number with the head of two heaps. After deciding we can insert in a heap in O(log n) time. After this insertion if the heaps are unbalanced, we can just move from one heap to another. which is again of O(log n) complexity. And now we can find the median in O(1) time. If two heaps contain same number of elements then median is the average of the head of two heaps. If one is greater, then median is the head of the larger heap.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;java-algorithm&#34;&gt;JAVA ALGORITHM&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, I found an algorithm in Java that can calculate the Running Median:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-java&#34; data-lang=&#34;java&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; java.util.Comparator&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; java.util.PriorityQueue&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; java.util.Random&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
 
 
&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;public&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;class&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;RunningMedian&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    PriorityQueue&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;Integer&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; upperQueue&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
    PriorityQueue&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;Integer&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; lowerQueue&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
 
    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;public&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;RunningMedian&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        lowerQueue&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; PriorityQueue&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;Integer&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;(&lt;/span&gt;
          20&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; Comparator&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;Integer&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;()&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
 
            &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;@Override&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;public&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;int&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;compare&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;Integer o1&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; Integer o2&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
 
                &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;o1&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;compareTo&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;o2&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
 
        &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;});&lt;/span&gt;
        upperQueue&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; PriorityQueue&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;Integer&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;();&lt;/span&gt;
        upperQueue&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;add&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;Integer&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;MAX_VALUE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
        lowerQueue&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;add&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;Integer&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;MIN_VALUE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
 
    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;public&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;double&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;getMedian&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;int&lt;/span&gt; num&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;//adding the number to proper heap
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;            &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;num&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;=&lt;/span&gt;upperQueue&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;peek&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;())&lt;/span&gt;
                upperQueue&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;add&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;num&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;else&lt;/span&gt;
                lowerQueue&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;add&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;num&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;//balancing the heaps
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;        &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;upperQueue&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;size&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;()-&lt;/span&gt;lowerQueue&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;size&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;()==&lt;/span&gt;2&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
            lowerQueue&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;add&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;upperQueue&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;poll&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;());&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;else&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;lowerQueue&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;size&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;()-&lt;/span&gt;upperQueue&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;size&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;()==&lt;/span&gt;2&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
            upperQueue&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;add&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;lowerQueue&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;poll&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;());&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;//returning the median
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;        &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;upperQueue&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;size&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;()==&lt;/span&gt;lowerQueue&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;size&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;())&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;upperQueue&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;peek&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;()+&lt;/span&gt;lowerQueue&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;peek&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;())/&lt;/span&gt;2&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;else&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;upperQueue&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;size&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;()&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;lowerQueue&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;size&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;())&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; upperQueue&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;peek&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;();&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;else&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; lowerQueue&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;peek&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;();&lt;/span&gt;
 
    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;public&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;static&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;void&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;main&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;String&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;[]&lt;/span&gt; args&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        Random random&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; Random&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;();&lt;/span&gt;
        RunningMedian runningMedian&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; RunningMedian&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;();&lt;/span&gt;
        System&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;out&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;println&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;num\tmedian&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;for&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;int&lt;/span&gt; i&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;0&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;i&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;50&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;;++&lt;/span&gt;i&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;int&lt;/span&gt; num&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;random&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;nextInt&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;100&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
            System&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;out&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;print&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;num&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
            System&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;out&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;print&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;\t&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
            System&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;out&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;println&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;
              runningMedian&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;getMedian&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;num&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;));&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
 
    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>8_R : TO INFINITY AND BEYOND</title>
      <link>https://lucarep.github.io/homework6/8_r/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lucarep.github.io/homework6/8_r/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents
 WHAT IS THE LAW OF LARGE NUMBERS(LLN)? WEAK LAW OF LARGE NUMBERS: STRONG LAW OF LARGE NUMBERS: WHAT IS THE CENTRAL LIMIT THEOREM? CONVERGENCE OF THE BINOMIAL TO THE NORMAL - Credits  WHAT IS THE LAW OF LARGE NUMBERS(LLN)? In probability theory, the law of large numbers (LLN) is a theorem that describes the result of performing the same experiment a large number of times. According to the law, the average of the results obtained from a large number of trials should be close to the expected value and will tend to become closer to the expected value as more trials are performed.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#what-is-the-law-of-large-numberslln&#34;&gt;WHAT IS THE LAW OF LARGE NUMBERS(LLN)?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#weak-law-of-large-numbers&#34;&gt;WEAK LAW OF LARGE NUMBERS:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#strong-law-of-large-numbers&#34;&gt;STRONG LAW OF LARGE NUMBERS:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#what-is-the-central-limit-theorem&#34;&gt;WHAT IS THE CENTRAL LIMIT THEOREM?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#convergence-of-the-binomial-to-the-normal&#34;&gt;CONVERGENCE OF THE BINOMIAL TO THE NORMAL&lt;/a&gt;
- &lt;a href=&#34;#credits&#34;&gt;Credits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-is-the-law-of-large-numberslln&#34;&gt;WHAT IS THE LAW OF LARGE NUMBERS(LLN)?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In probability theory, the law of large numbers (LLN) is a theorem that describes the result of performing the same experiment a large number of times. According to the law, the average of the results obtained from a large number of trials should be close to the expected value and will tend to become closer to the expected value as more trials are performed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The LLN is important because it guarantees stable long-term results for the averages of some random events. For example, while a casino may lose money in a single spin of the roulette wheel, its earnings will tend towards a predictable percentage over a large number of spins. Any winning streak by a player will eventually be overcome by the parameters of the game. It is important to remember that the law only applies (as the name indicates) when a large number of observations is considered. There is no principle that a small number of observations will coincide with the expected value or that a streak of one value will immediately be “balanced” by the others (see the gambler’s fallacy).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if I told you that there are two different laws of large numbers?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;weak-law-of-large-numbers&#34;&gt;WEAK LAW OF LARGE NUMBERS:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The weak law of large numbers states that the sample average converges in probability towards the expected value:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$$ \overline{X_{n}} \rightarrow \mu $$
When:
$$ n \rightarrow \infty $$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is, for any positive number ε:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$$ lim_{n \rightarrow \infty} Pr(|\overline{X_{n}} - \mu| &amp;gt; \epsilon) = 0$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interpreting this result, the weak law states that for any nonzero margin specified, no matter how small, with a sufficiently large sample there will be a very high probability that the average of the observations will be close to the expected value; that is, within the margin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;strong-law-of-large-numbers&#34;&gt;STRONG LAW OF LARGE NUMBERS:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The strong law of large numbers states that the sample average converges almost surely to the expected value:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$$ \overline{X_{n}} \rightarrow \mu $$
When:
$$ n \rightarrow \infty $$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$$ Pr(lim_{n \rightarrow \infty} \overline{X_{n}} = \mu) = 1$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What this means is that the probability that, as the number of trials n goes to infinity, the average of the observations converges to the expected value, is equal to one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almost sure convergence is also called strong convergence of random variables. This version is called the strong law because random variables which converge strongly (almost surely) are guaranteed to converge weakly (in probability). However the weak law is known to hold in certain conditions where the strong law does not hold and then the convergence is only weak (in probability).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-is-the-central-limit-theorem&#34;&gt;WHAT IS THE CENTRAL LIMIT THEOREM?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In probability theory, the central limit theorem (CLT) establishes that, in many situations, when independent random variables are added, their properly normalised sum tends toward a normal distribution (informally a bell curve) even if the original variables themselves are not normally distributed. The theorem is a key concept in probability theory because it implies that probabilistic and statistical methods that work for normal distributions can be applicable to many problems involving other types of distributions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If: $$ X_{1},X_{2},&amp;hellip;X_{n}$$ are random samples each of size n taken from a population with overall mean μ and
finite variance and if X is the sample mean, the limiting form of the distribution of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$$ Z = (\frac{\overline{X_{n}} - \mu}{\frac{\sigma}{\sqrt{n}}})$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;as:
$$ n \to \infty $$
is the standard normal distribution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, suppose that a sample is obtained containing many observations, each observation being randomly generated in a way that does not depend on the values of the other observations, and that the arithmetic mean of the observed values is computed. If this procedure is performed many times, the central limit theorem says that the probability distribution of the average will closely approximate a normal distribution. A simple example of this is that if one flips a coin many times, the probability of getting a given number of heads will approach a normal distribution, with the mean equal to half the total number of flips. At the limit of an infinite number of flips, it will equal a normal distribution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The central limit theorem has several variants. In its common form, the random variables must be identically distributed. In variants, convergence of the mean to the normal distribution also occurs for non-identical distributions or for non-independent observations, if they comply with certain conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whatever the form of the population distribution, the sampling distribution tends to a Gaussian, and its dispersion is given by the Central Limit Theorem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;convergence-of-the-binomial-to-the-normal&#34;&gt;CONVERGENCE OF THE BINOMIAL TO THE NORMAL&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;first of all, we have to talk about the de Moivre-Laplace theorem, which is a special case of the central limit theorem; it tells us that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The binomial distribution can be approximated to a normal distribution, under some conditions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider a series of n independent trials, each resulting in one of two possible outcomes, a success with probability:
$$(0 &amp;lt; p &amp;lt; 1)$$
and failure with probability:
$$q = (1 - p)$$
Let &lt;em&gt;Xn&lt;/em&gt; denote the number of success in these &lt;em&gt;n&lt;/em&gt; trials.
Then the random variable &lt;em&gt;Xn&lt;/em&gt;, is said to have binomial distribution with parameters &lt;em&gt;n&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;p, b(n,p)&lt;/em&gt;.So, the probability density function(pdf) of &lt;em&gt;Xn&lt;/em&gt; is given by:
$$P(X) = \frac{n!}{(n - X)!X!} \cdot (p)^{X}\cdot(q)^{n - X}$$
The mean and variance of the binomial r.v. &lt;em&gt;Xn&lt;/em&gt; are given, respectively, by:
$$ E[X_{n}] = \mu = np $$
$$ Var[X_{n}] = \sigma^{2} = nqp = np(1-p)$$
For sufficently large *n*, the following random variable has a standard normal distribution:
$$z = \frac{\chi - \mu}{\sigma} = N(0,1)$$
That is:
The general form of Normal distribution probability density function is:
$$f(x) = \frac{1}{\sigma\sqrt{2\pi}}e^{-\frac{1}{2}(\frac{x - \mu}{\sigma})^{2}}$$
For a binomial distribution, as *n* grows large, for *k* in the neighborhood of *np* we can approximate:
$$\binom{n}{k}p^{k}q^{n - k} \approx \frac{1}{\sqrt{2\pi npq}}e^{-\frac{(k - np)^{2}}{2npq}}$$
$$p + q = 1, p,q &amp;gt; 0$$
in the sense that the ratio of the left-hand side to the right-hand side converges to:
$$1 \text{ as } n \to \infty$$
In conclusion:
The normal distribution is generally considered to be a pretty good approximation for the binomial distribution when *np ≥ 5 and n(1 – p) ≥ 5*.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&#34;credits&#34;&gt;Credits&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to thank and mention some resources that I found particularly helpful in the writing of this post:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Law_of_large_numbers&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Law_of_large_numbers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Expected_value&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Expected_value&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Central_limit_theorem&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Central_limit_theorem&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.statisticshowto.com/probability-and-statistics/binomial-theorem/binomial-distribution-formula/&#34;&gt;https://www.statisticshowto.com/probability-and-statistics/binomial-theorem/binomial-distribution-formula/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.real-statistics.com/binomial-and-related-distributions/relationship-binomial-and-normal-distributions/&#34;&gt;https://www.real-statistics.com/binomial-and-related-distributions/relationship-binomial-and-normal-distributions/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5_RA</title>
      <link>https://lucarep.github.io/homework5/5_ra/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lucarep.github.io/homework5/5_ra/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents
 WHAT IS A RANDOM VARIABLE? WHY THEY ARE IMPORTANT? HOW WE CAN GENERATE RANDOM NUMBERS? PSEUDO RANDOM TRUE RANDOM UNIFORM RANDOM GENERATOR - Credits  WHAT IS A RANDOM VARIABLE? Informally is a variable that is described as a variable whose values depend on outcomes of a random phenomenon. In formal a random variable is understood as a measurable function defined on a probability space that maps from the sample space to the real numbers.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#what-is-a-random-variable&#34;&gt;WHAT IS A RANDOM VARIABLE?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#why-they-are-important&#34;&gt;WHY THEY ARE IMPORTANT?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#how-we-can-generate-random-numbers&#34;&gt;HOW WE CAN GENERATE RANDOM NUMBERS?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#pseudo-random&#34;&gt;PSEUDO RANDOM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#true-random&#34;&gt;TRUE RANDOM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#uniform-random-generator&#34;&gt;UNIFORM RANDOM GENERATOR&lt;/a&gt;
- &lt;a href=&#34;#credits&#34;&gt;Credits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-is-a-random-variable&#34;&gt;WHAT IS A RANDOM VARIABLE?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Informally is a variable that is described as a variable whose values depend on outcomes of a random phenomenon. In formal a random variable is understood as a measurable function defined on a probability space that maps from the sample space to the real numbers.
So the random variable is defined as a function, that must be measurable, which performs the mapping of the outcomes of a random process to a numeric value. Also, keep in mind that random variables can be both discrete or continuous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;why-they-are-important&#34;&gt;WHY THEY ARE IMPORTANT?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Up until now we have always discussed problems where you made observations and then collected data, why do we now need random numbers? Well, there is a large class of experimental problems that require a large number of random digits and normal deviates of high quality. These applications are called Monte Carlo methods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-we-can-generate-random-numbers&#34;&gt;HOW WE CAN GENERATE RANDOM NUMBERS?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a person, generating a random number is quite trivial, however for a computer there is no such concept, in this sense there are two categories:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pseudo Random Number Generator (PRNG)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;True Random Number Generator (TRNG)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;pseudo-random&#34;&gt;PSEUDO RANDOM&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Software-generated random numbers only are pseudorandom. They are not truly random because the computer uses an algorithm based on a distribution, and are not secure because they rely on deterministic, predictable algorithms. Since a seed number can be set to replicate the “random” numbers generated, it is possible to predict the numbers if the seed is known. Pseudorandom number generation in everyday tools such as Python and Excel are based on the Mersenne Twister algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An example use of PRNGs is in key stream generation. Stream ciphers, such as Chacha, encrypt plaintext messages by applying an encryption algorithm with a pseudorandom cipher digit stream (keystream). Keystreams of some block cipher modes, such as AES CTR (counter) mode, act as a stream cipher and can also be regarded as pseudorandom number generation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;true-random&#34;&gt;TRUE RANDOM&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For truly random numbers, the computer must use some external physical variable that is unpredictable, such as radioactive decay of isotopes or airwave static, rather than by an algorithm. At the quantum level, subatomic particles have completely random behavior, making them ideal variables of an unpredictable system. Most higher end microcontrollers have TRNG sources, which wolfSSL can use as a direct random source or as a seed for our PRNG. Intel RDRAND, a silicon-based TRNG, is supported by wolfSSL. he problem with them was the bandwidth - the amount of entropy they could generate wasn&amp;rsquo;t very high so they were used for seeds of pseudorandom algorithms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;uniform-random-generator&#34;&gt;UNIFORM RANDOM GENERATOR&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The binomial distribution with parameters n and p is the discrete probability distribution of the number of successes in a sequence of n independent experiments, each asking a yes–no question, and each with its own Boolean-valued outcome: success/yes (with probability p) or failure/no(with probability q = 1 − p).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34; data-lang=&#34;python&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;pseudo_binomial&lt;/span&gt;(n&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;100&lt;/span&gt;,p&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;0.5&lt;/span&gt;,size&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;):
    binom &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; []
    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; _ &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; range(size):
        t &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; time&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;perf_counter()
        seed &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; int(&lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;**&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;9&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;float(str(t&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;int(t))[&lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;:]))
        U &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; pseudo_uniform(size&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;n,seed&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;seed)
        Y &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; (U &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;=&lt;/span&gt; p)&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;astype(int)
        binom&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;append(np&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;sum(Y))
    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; binom
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Bernoulli distribution, (a special case of the binomial distribution where a single trial is conducted (so n would be 1 for such a binomial distribution)).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34; data-lang=&#34;python&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;pseudo_bernoulli&lt;/span&gt;(p&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;0.5&lt;/span&gt;,size&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;):
    t &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; time&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;perf_counter()
    seed &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; int(&lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;**&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;9&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;float(str(t&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;int(t))[&lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;:]))
    B &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; pseudo_uniform(seed&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;seed,size&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;size)
    B &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; (B&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;=&lt;/span&gt;p)&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;astype(int)
    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; B
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Poisson distribution is a discrete probability distribution that expresses the probability of a given number of events occurring in a fixed interval of time or space if these events occur with a known constant mean rate and independently of the time since the last event. The Poisson distribution can also be used for the number of events in other specified intervals such as distance, area or volume.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34; data-lang=&#34;python&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;pseudo_poisson&lt;/span&gt;(alpha,size&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;):
    poisson &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; []
    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; _ &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; range(size):
        t &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; time&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;perf_counter()
        seed &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; int(&lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;**&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;9&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;float(str(t&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;int(t))[&lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;:]))
        U &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; pseudo_uniform(size&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;alpha,seed&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;seed)
        X,P,i &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;,&lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;,&lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;while&lt;/span&gt; P &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;=&lt;/span&gt; np&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;exp(&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;alpha):
            P &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; U[i]&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;P
            x&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;+=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;
            i&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;+=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;
        poisson&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;append(X)
    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; np&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;array(poisson)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h6 id=&#34;credits&#34;&gt;Credits&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to thank and mention some resources that I found particularly helpful in the writing of this post:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wolfssl.com/true-random-vs-pseudorandom-number-generation/&#34;&gt;https://www.wolfssl.com/true-random-vs-pseudorandom-number-generation/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://softwareengineering.stackexchange.com/questions/109724/how-do-random-number-generators-work&#34;&gt;https://softwareengineering.stackexchange.com/questions/109724/how-do-random-number-generators-work&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://towardsdatascience.com/how-to-generate-random-variables-from-scratch-no-library-used-4b71eb3c8dc7&#34;&gt;https://towardsdatascience.com/how-to-generate-random-variables-from-scratch-no-library-used-4b71eb3c8dc7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>7_R : BAYES&#39; THEOREM</title>
      <link>https://lucarep.github.io/homework5/7_r/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lucarep.github.io/homework5/7_r/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents
 INTRO - BUT, WHY? A BIT OF MATH AN EXAMPLE: NOW, BACK TO SEARCH ENGINES. BAYESIAN VS FREQUENTIST - LET&amp;rsquo;S SEE WHY - Credits  INTRO Bayes&#39; Theorem, is certainly one of the most important ever discovered, the reason, is that even today we use it in many different areas. Take for example a common search on the internet: &amp;ldquo;movie automatic shoe laces&amp;rdquo; the search engine will show us results also of the movie &amp;ldquo;Back to the Future&amp;rdquo;.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#intro&#34;&gt;INTRO&lt;/a&gt;
- &lt;a href=&#34;#but-why&#34;&gt;BUT, WHY?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#a-bit-of-math&#34;&gt;A BIT OF MATH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#an-example&#34;&gt;AN EXAMPLE:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#now-back-to-search-engines&#34;&gt;NOW, BACK TO SEARCH ENGINES.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#bayesian-vs-frequentist&#34;&gt;BAYESIAN VS FREQUENTIST&lt;/a&gt;
- &lt;a href=&#34;#lets-see-why&#34;&gt;LET&amp;rsquo;S SEE WHY&lt;/a&gt;
- &lt;a href=&#34;#credits&#34;&gt;Credits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;INTRO&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bayes&#39; Theorem, is certainly one of the most important ever discovered, the reason, is that even today we use it in many different areas. Take for example a common search on the internet:
&amp;ldquo;movie automatic shoe laces&amp;rdquo;
the search engine will show us results also of the movie &amp;ldquo;Back to the Future&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;but-why&#34;&gt;BUT, WHY?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mean, the search engine doesn&amp;rsquo;t look at the movie, right? Well yes, but actually no, in the sense, it knows because many others have previously watched it and then analyzes the previous queries to understand what others are probably looking for, all this is calculated thanks to Bayes&#39; Theorem&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-bit-of-math&#34;&gt;A BIT OF MATH&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bayes&#39; Theorem is a way of finding a probability when we know certain other probabilities. The formula is:
$$ P(A|B) = \frac{P(A)P(B|A)}{P(B)}$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which tells us:
how often A happens given that B happens, written P(A|B)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we know:
how often B happens given that A happens, written P(B|A), and how likely A is on its own, written P(A)
and how likely B is on its own, written P(B)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;an-example&#34;&gt;AN EXAMPLE:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;dangerous fires are rare (1%)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;but smoke is fairly common (10%) due to barbecues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;and 90% of dangerous fires make smoke&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can then discover the probability of dangerous Fire when there is Smoke:
$$ P(Fire|Smoke) = \frac{P(Fire)P(Smoke|Fire)}{P(Smoke)} = \frac{0.01 \cdot 0.9}{0.1} = 0.09$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So it is still worth checking out any smoke to be sure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;now-back-to-search-engines&#34;&gt;NOW, BACK TO SEARCH ENGINES.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Search Engines take this idea and scale it up a lot (plus some other tricks).
It makes them look like they can read your mind!
It can also be used for mail filters, music recommendation services and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;now you can guess why it is so important, but to be explicit, we can say that it allows us to draw conclusions about the population by knowing the sample.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;bayesian-vs-frequentist&#34;&gt;BAYESIAN VS FREQUENTIST&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We begin our study with a simple question:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the probability that the coin in my palm is heads?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the coin lands I already know the answer, but you still don&amp;rsquo;t, the answer you give will tell us if you are more inclined towards Bayesian or Frequentist thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;lets-see-why&#34;&gt;LET&amp;rsquo;S SEE WHY&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Frequentist: “There’s no probability about it. I may not know the answer, but that doesn’t change the fact that if the coin is heads up, the probability is 100%, and if the coin is tails up, the probability is 0%.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bayesian: “For me, the probability is 50%! For you, it’s whatever it is for you.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can summarize the above, with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Frequentist: The parameter is not a random variable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bayesian: The parameter is a random variable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s look at another example that I think is very clear:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine this situation, I&amp;rsquo;m at home and I misplace my phone, to find it I use the app to make it beeping and the phone starts doing it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Frequentist Reasoning: I can hear the phone beeping. I also have a mental model which helps me identify the area from which the sound is coming. Therefore, upon hearing the beep, I infer the area of my home I must search to locate the phone&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bayesian Reasoning: I can hear the phone beeping. Now, apart from a mental model which helps me identify the area from which the sound is coming from, I also know the locations where I have misplaced the phone in the past. So, I combine my inferences using the beeps and my prior information about the locations I have misplaced the phone in the past to identify an area I must search to locate the phone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&#34;credits&#34;&gt;Credits&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to thank and mention some resources that I found particularly helpful in the writing of this post:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mathsisfun.com/data/bayes-theorem.html&#34;&gt;https://www.mathsisfun.com/data/bayes-theorem.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://towardsdatascience.com/statistics-are-you-bayesian-or-frequentist-4943f953f21b&#34;&gt;https://towardsdatascience.com/statistics-are-you-bayesian-or-frequentist-4943f953f21b&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://stats.stackexchange.com/questions/22/bayesian-and-frequentist-reasoning-in-plain-english&#34;&gt;https://stats.stackexchange.com/questions/22/bayesian-and-frequentist-reasoning-in-plain-english&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6_R</title>
      <link>https://lucarep.github.io/homework5/6_r/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lucarep.github.io/homework5/6_r/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents
 INTRO REAL WORLD EXAMPLES - BUT, WHY? WHAT ROLE DO PROBABILITY DISTRIBUTIONS PLAY IN STATISTICAL INFERENCE? SOME EXAMPLES: - Credits  INTRO When we collect data, we often also collect errors so, this implies some sort of chance or random variation, in this, probability plays a fundamental role, so it is important to understand how to apply it
REAL WORLD EXAMPLES As we can imagine from the initial premise, statistics and probability are broadly related.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#intro&#34;&gt;INTRO&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#real-world-examples&#34;&gt;REAL WORLD EXAMPLES&lt;/a&gt;
- &lt;a href=&#34;#but-why&#34;&gt;BUT, WHY?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#what-role-do-probability-distributions-play-in-statistical-inference&#34;&gt;WHAT ROLE DO PROBABILITY DISTRIBUTIONS PLAY IN STATISTICAL INFERENCE?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#some-examples&#34;&gt;SOME EXAMPLES:&lt;/a&gt;
- &lt;a href=&#34;#credits&#34;&gt;Credits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;INTRO&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we collect data, we often also collect errors so, this implies some sort of chance or random variation, 
in this, &lt;strong&gt;probability&lt;/strong&gt; plays a fundamental role, so it is important to understand how to apply it&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;real-world-examples&#34;&gt;REAL WORLD EXAMPLES&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we can imagine from the initial premise, statistics and probability are broadly related. Take for example a scientist who performs a measurement, the result of this measurement has a certain amount of chance associated with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;but-why&#34;&gt;BUT, WHY?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, we consider for example electrical noise in the instrumentation used, small fluctuations in environmental conditions and also human error. The scientist therefore, cannot expect to receive the same result from measurements in every case, even an anthropologist when considering a small group of people compared to a large population, will have some random variations that must be taken into account in the study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-role-do-probability-distributions-play-in-statistical-inference&#34;&gt;WHAT ROLE DO PROBABILITY DISTRIBUTIONS PLAY IN STATISTICAL INFERENCE?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Randomization is important for collecting data, the idea that the possible observations are known but it&amp;rsquo;s yet unknown which possibility will prevail. What will happen, depends on probability. The probability is the proportion of the number of times that a certain observation is prevalent in a long sequence of similar observations. The fact that the sequence is long, is important, because the longer the sequence, the more accurate the probability. Then the sample proportion becomes more like the population proportion. Probabilities can also be measured in percentages (such as 70%) instead of proportions (such as 0.7). A specific branch within statistics deals with subjective probabilities, called &lt;strong&gt;Bayesian statistics&lt;/strong&gt;. However, most of statistics is about regular probabilities.
A probability is written like P(A), where P is the probability and A is an outcome. If two outcomes are possible and they exclude each other, then the chance that B happens is 1- P(A).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;some-examples&#34;&gt;SOME EXAMPLES:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;magine research about people&amp;rsquo;s favorite colors, whether this is mostly red and blue. Again the assumption is made that the possibilities exclude each other without overlapping. The chance that someone&amp;rsquo;s favorite color is red (A) or blue (B), is P(A of B) = P (A) + P (B).
Next, imagine research that encompasses multiple questions. The research seeks to investigate how many married people have kids. Then you can multiply the chance that someone is married (A) with the chance that someone has kids (B).The formula for this is: P(A and B) = P(A) * P(B if also A). Because there is a connection between A and B, this is called a conditional probability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&#34;credits&#34;&gt;Credits&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to thank and mention some resources that I found particularly helpful in the writing of this post:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.universalclass.com/articles/math/what-is-probability-in-statistics.htm&#34;&gt;https://www.universalclass.com/articles/math/what-is-probability-in-statistics.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.worldsupporter.org/en/chapter/65146-what-role-do-probability-distributions-play-statistical-inference-chapter-4&#34;&gt;https://www.worldsupporter.org/en/chapter/65146-what-role-do-probability-distributions-play-statistical-inference-chapter-4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5_R</title>
      <link>https://lucarep.github.io/homework4/5_r/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lucarep.github.io/homework4/5_r/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents
 INTRODUCTION TO CENTRAL TENDENCY SO, WHY THERE ARE SO MANY WAYS TO MEASURE CENTRAL TENDENCY? 🤔 ARITHMETIC MEAN - When not to use the mean: MEDIAN MODE INTRODUCTION TO DISPERSION STANDARD DEVIATION VARIANCE INTRODUCTION TO DISTANCE MINKOWSKI DISTANCE MANHATTAN DISTANCE: - When is Manhattan distance metric preferred in ML? EUCLIDEAN DISTANCE: HAMMING DISTANCE COSINE DISTANCE - Where is it used? - Credits  INTRODUCTION TO CENTRAL TENDENCY A measure of central tendency is a single value that attempts to describe a set of data by identifying the central position within that set of data.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#introduction-to-central-tendency&#34;&gt;INTRODUCTION TO CENTRAL TENDENCY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#so-why-there-are-so-many-ways-to-measure-central-tendency-&#34;&gt;SO, WHY THERE ARE SO MANY WAYS TO MEASURE CENTRAL TENDENCY? 🤔&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#arithmetic-mean&#34;&gt;ARITHMETIC MEAN&lt;/a&gt;
- &lt;a href=&#34;#when-not-to-use-the-mean&#34;&gt;When not to use the mean:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#median&#34;&gt;MEDIAN&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#mode&#34;&gt;MODE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#introduction-to-dispersion&#34;&gt;INTRODUCTION TO DISPERSION&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#standard-deviation&#34;&gt;STANDARD DEVIATION&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#variance&#34;&gt;VARIANCE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#introduction-to-distance&#34;&gt;INTRODUCTION TO DISTANCE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#minkowski-distance&#34;&gt;MINKOWSKI DISTANCE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#manhattan-distance&#34;&gt;MANHATTAN DISTANCE:&lt;/a&gt;
- &lt;a href=&#34;#when-is-manhattan-distance-metric-preferred-in-ml&#34;&gt;When is Manhattan distance metric preferred in ML?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#euclidean-distance&#34;&gt;EUCLIDEAN DISTANCE:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#hamming-distance&#34;&gt;HAMMING DISTANCE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#cosine-distance&#34;&gt;COSINE DISTANCE&lt;/a&gt;
- &lt;a href=&#34;#where-is-it-used&#34;&gt;Where is it used?&lt;/a&gt;
- &lt;a href=&#34;#credits&#34;&gt;Credits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction-to-central-tendency&#34;&gt;INTRODUCTION TO CENTRAL TENDENCY&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A measure of central tendency is a single value that &lt;strong&gt;attempts to describe a set of data by identifying the central position within that set of data&lt;/strong&gt;. As such, measures of central tendency are sometimes called measures of &lt;strong&gt;central location&lt;/strong&gt;. They are also classed as &lt;strong&gt;summary statistics&lt;/strong&gt;. The &lt;strong&gt;mean&lt;/strong&gt; (often called the average) is most likely the measure of central tendency that you are most familiar with, but there are others, such as the &lt;strong&gt;median&lt;/strong&gt; and the &lt;strong&gt;mode&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;so-why-there-are-so-many-ways-to-measure-central-tendency-&#34;&gt;SO, WHY THERE ARE SO MANY WAYS TO MEASURE CENTRAL TENDENCY? 🤔&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mean, median and mode are all &lt;strong&gt;valid&lt;/strong&gt; measures of central tendency, but under different conditions, some measures of central tendency become more &lt;strong&gt;appropriate&lt;/strong&gt; to use than others. In the following sections, we will look at the mean, mode and median, and learn how to calculate them and under what conditions they are most appropriate to be used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;arithmetic-mean&#34;&gt;ARITHMETIC MEAN&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mean (or average) is the most popular and well known measure of central tendency. It can be used with both &lt;strong&gt;discrete and continuous data&lt;/strong&gt;, although its use is most &lt;strong&gt;often with continuous data&lt;/strong&gt;. The mean is equal to the sum of all the values in the data set divided by the number of values in the data set. So, if we have n values  the sample mean, is:
$$  \overline{x} = \frac{x_{1} + x_{2} + &amp;hellip; + x_{n}}{n}$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may have noticed that the above formula refers to the &lt;strong&gt;sample mean&lt;/strong&gt;. So, why have we called it a sample mean? This is because, in statistics, samples and populations have very different meanings and these differences are very important, even if, in the case of the mean, they are calculated in the same way. To acknowledge that we are calculating the population mean and not the sample mean, we use the Greek lower case letter &amp;ldquo;mu&amp;rdquo;, denoted as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$$ \mu = \frac{\sum x}{n}$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&#34;when-not-to-use-the-mean&#34;&gt;When not to use the mean:&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mean has one main disadvantage: it is particularly susceptible to the influence of outliers. These are values that are unusual compared to the rest of the data set by being especially small or large in numerical value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;median&#34;&gt;MEDIAN&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The median is the middle score for a set of data that has been arranged in &lt;strong&gt;order of magnitude&lt;/strong&gt;. The median is &lt;strong&gt;less affected by outliers and skewed data&lt;/strong&gt;. In order to calculate the median, suppose we have the data below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;65&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;55&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;89&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;56&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;35&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;14&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;56&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;55&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;87&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;45&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;92&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We first need to rearrange that data into order of magnitude (smallest first):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;14&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;35&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;45&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;55&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;55&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;56&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;56&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;65&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;87&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;89&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;92&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our median mark is the middle mark - in this case, 56. It is the middle mark because there are 5 scores &lt;strong&gt;before&lt;/strong&gt; it and 5 scores &lt;strong&gt;after&lt;/strong&gt; it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;mode&#34;&gt;MODE&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mode is the most frequent score in our data set. On a histogram it represents the highest bar in a bar chart or histogram. You can, therefore, sometimes consider the mode as being the most popular option. An example of a mode is presented below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://lucarep.github.io/img/mode-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;mode&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Normally, the mode is used for categorical data where we wish to know which is the most common category.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction-to-dispersion&#34;&gt;INTRODUCTION TO DISPERSION&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dispersion in statistics is a way of describing how spread out a set of data is. When a data set has a large value, the values in the set are widely scattered; when it is small the items in the set are tightly clustered. Very basically, this set of data has a small value:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$$1,2,2,3,3,4$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and this set has a wider one:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$$0,1,20,30,40,100$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The spread of a data set can be described by a range of descriptive statistics including &lt;strong&gt;variance, standard deviation, and interquartile range&lt;/strong&gt;. Spread can also be shown in graphs: &lt;strong&gt;dot plots, boxplots, and stem and leaf plots&lt;/strong&gt; have a greater distance with samples that have a larger dispersion and vice versa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;standard-deviation&#34;&gt;STANDARD DEVIATION&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;probably the most common measure. It tells you how spread out numbers are from the mean:
$$ \sigma = \sqrt{\frac{\sum|x - \overline{x}|^{2}}{n}}$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;variance&#34;&gt;VARIANCE&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The variance has a similar meaning to the standard deviation, however in some cases it is easier to calculate because it does not use the square root:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$$ \sigma^{2} = \sqrt{\frac{\sum|x - \overline{x}|}{n}}$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction-to-distance&#34;&gt;INTRODUCTION TO DISTANCE&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Citing Wikipedia:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In statistics, probability theory, and information theory, a statistical distance quantifies the distance between two statistical objects, which can be two random variables, or two probability distributions or samples, or the distance can be between an individual sample point and a population or a wider sample of points.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the concept of distance is very important in &lt;strong&gt;machine learning&lt;/strong&gt;, however, contrary to what you might think from the definition there is no single concept of distance, but there are several types that we will see below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;minkowski-distance&#34;&gt;MINKOWSKI DISTANCE&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Wikipedia:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“A Normed vector space is a vector space on which a norm is defined.” 
Suppose A is a vector space then a norm on A is a real-valued function ||A||which satisfies below conditions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zero Vector: Zero vector will have zero length.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scalar Factor: The direction of the vector doesn’t change when you multiply it with a positive number though its length will be changed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Triangle Inequality: If the distance is a norm then the calculated distance between two points will always be a straight line.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The distance can be calculated using the below formula:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$$ (\sum_{i = 1}^{n} |x_{i} - y_{i}|^p)^\frac{1}{p}$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Minkowski distance is a generalized distance metric. We can manipulate the above formula by substituting ‘p’ to calculate the distance between two data points in different ways. Thus, Minkowski Distance is also known as &lt;strong&gt;Lp norm distance&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some common values of ‘p’ are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;p = 1, Manhattan Distance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;p = 2, Euclidean Distance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;p = infinity, Chebychev Distance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;manhattan-distance&#34;&gt;MANHATTAN DISTANCE:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We use Manhattan distance, also known as &lt;strong&gt;city block distance&lt;/strong&gt;, or &lt;strong&gt;taxicab geometry&lt;/strong&gt; if we need to calculate the distance between two data points in a grid-like path. Manhattan distance metric can be understood with the help of a simple example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://lucarep.github.io/img/manhattan.png&#34; alt=&#34;Manhattan&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the above picture, imagine each cell to be a building, and the grid lines to be roads. Now if I want to travel from Point A to Point B marked in the image and follow the red or the yellow path. We see that the path is not straight and there are turns. In this case, we use the Manhattan distance metric to calculate the distance walked.
We can get the equation for Manhattan distance by substituting p = 1 in the Minkowski distance formula. The formula is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$$ d = \sum_{i = 1}^{n} |x_{i} - y_{i}|$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&#34;when-is-manhattan-distance-metric-preferred-in-ml&#34;&gt;When is Manhattan distance metric preferred in ML?&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Manhattan Distance is preferred over the Euclidean distance metric as the dimension of the data increases. This occurs due to something known as the ‘curse of dimensionality’.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;euclidean-distance&#34;&gt;EUCLIDEAN DISTANCE:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Euclidean distance is the straight line distance between 2 data points in a plane.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://lucarep.github.io/img/euclidean.png&#34; alt=&#34;Euclidean&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is calculated using the Minkowski Distance formula by setting ‘p’ value to 2, thus, also known as the L2 norm distance metric. The formula is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$$d = \sqrt{\sum_{i = 1}^{n} |x_{i} - y_{i}|^2}$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This formula is similar to the Pythagorean theorem formula, Thus it is also known as the &lt;strong&gt;Pythagorean Theorem&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;hamming-distance&#34;&gt;HAMMING DISTANCE&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hamming distance is a metric for comparing two binary data strings. While comparing two binary strings of equal length, Hamming distance is the number of bit positions in which the two bits are different.
The Hamming distance between two strings, a and b is denoted as d(a,b).
In order to calculate the Hamming distance between two strings, and, we perform their XOR operation, (a ⊕ b), and then count the total number of 1s in the resultant string.
Suppose there are two strings 11011001 and 10011101.
11011001 ⊕ 10011101 = 01000100. Since, this contains two 1s, the Hamming distance, d(11011001, 10011101) = 2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;cosine-distance&#34;&gt;COSINE DISTANCE&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cosine distance &amp;amp; Cosine Similarity metric is mainly used to find similarities between two data points. As the cosine distance between the data points increases, the cosine similarity, or the amount of similarity decreases, and vice versa. Thus, Points closer to each other are more similar than points that are far away from each other. Cosine similarity is given by Cos θ, and cosine distance is 1- Cos θ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&#34;where-is-it-used&#34;&gt;Where is it used?&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cosine metric is mainly used in Collaborative Filtering based recommendation systems to offer future recommendations to users.
Taking the example of a movie recommendation system, Suppose one user (User #1) has watched movies like The Fault in our Stars, and The Notebook, which are of romantic genres, and another user (User #2) has watched movies like The Proposal, and Notting Hill, which are also of romantic genres. So the recommendation system will use this data to recommend User #1 to see The Proposal, and Notting Hill as User #1 and User #2 both prefer the romantic genre and its likely that User #1 will like to watch another romantic genre movie and not a horror one.
Similarly, Suppose User #1 loves to watch movies based on horror, and User #2 loves the romance genre. In this case, User #2 won’t be suggested to watch a horror movie as there is no similarity between the romantic genre and the horror genre.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&#34;credits&#34;&gt;Credits&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to thank and mention some resources that I found particularly helpful in the writing of this post:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://statistics.laerd.com/statistical-guides/measures-central-tendency-mean-mode-median.php&#34;&gt;https://statistics.laerd.com/statistical-guides/measures-central-tendency-mean-mode-median.php&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.statisticshowto.com/dispersion/&#34;&gt;https://www.statisticshowto.com/dispersion/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@kunal_gohrani/different-types-of-distance-metrics-used-in-machine-learning-e9928c5e26c7&#34;&gt;https://medium.com/@kunal_gohrani/different-types-of-distance-metrics-used-in-machine-learning-e9928c5e26c7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4_RA</title>
      <link>https://lucarep.github.io/homework4/4_ra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lucarep.github.io/homework4/4_ra/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents
 WHAT IS A WINDOW? WHAT IS A VIEWPORT? WHAT IS WINDOW TO VIEWPORT TRANSFORMATION? C PROGRAM FROM WINDOW TO TO VIEWPORT TRANSFORMATION - Credits  WHAT IS A WINDOW? We can see a window like a region used for displaying a particular object.
WHAT IS A VIEWPORT? Each device has it&amp;rsquo;s own coordinate, so, we can see a viewport as a device coordinate after it got normalized.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#what-is-a-window&#34;&gt;WHAT IS A WINDOW?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#what-is-a-viewport&#34;&gt;WHAT IS A VIEWPORT?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#what-is-window-to-viewport-transformation&#34;&gt;WHAT IS WINDOW TO VIEWPORT TRANSFORMATION?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#c-program-from-window-to-to-viewport-transformation&#34;&gt;C PROGRAM FROM WINDOW TO TO VIEWPORT TRANSFORMATION&lt;/a&gt;
- &lt;a href=&#34;#credits&#34;&gt;Credits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-is-a-window&#34;&gt;WHAT IS A WINDOW?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can see a window like a region used for displaying a particular object.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-is-a-viewport&#34;&gt;WHAT IS A VIEWPORT?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each device has it&amp;rsquo;s own coordinate, so, we can see a viewport as a device coordinate after it got &lt;strong&gt;normalized&lt;/strong&gt;.
so what we do is mapping a part of the screen to display an object. In other words, world coordinate gets translated into device coordinate to fit in it&amp;rsquo;s relative perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-is-window-to-viewport-transformation&#34;&gt;WHAT IS WINDOW TO VIEWPORT TRANSFORMATION?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in essence the process described a moment ago, that is, transforming coordinates of the world into those of the device. In most cases the size of an object mapped in the viewport is &lt;strong&gt;smaller&lt;/strong&gt; than the window, but there are cases where we have &lt;strong&gt;larger&lt;/strong&gt; dimensions than the window.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://lucarep.github.io/img/viewport.png&#34; alt=&#34;Viewport&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;c-program-from-window-to-to-viewport-transformation&#34;&gt;C PROGRAM FROM WINDOW TO TO VIEWPORT TRANSFORMATION&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-c&#34; data-lang=&#34;c&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;#include&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;graphics.h&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;#include&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;conio.h&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;#include&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;stdio.h&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;void&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;main&lt;/span&gt; ()
{
  &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;int&lt;/span&gt; W_xmax, W_ymax, W_xmin, W_ymin;
  &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;int&lt;/span&gt; V_xmax, V_ymax, V_xmin, V_ymin;
  &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;float&lt;/span&gt; sx, sy;
  &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;int&lt;/span&gt; x, x1, x2, y, y1, y2;
  &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;int&lt;/span&gt; gr &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; DETECT, gm;
  initgraph (&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt;gr, &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt;gm, &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;C:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;\\&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;TURBOC3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;\\&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;BGI&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;);
  printf (&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;\n&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;****** Window to Viewport ***********&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;\n&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;);
  printf (&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;Enter the coordinates for triangle &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;\n&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt; x and y = &amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;);
  scanf (&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;%d %d&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt;x, &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt;y);
  printf (&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;\n&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt; x1 and y1 = &amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;);
  scanf (&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;%d %d&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt;x1, &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt;y1);
  printf (&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;\n&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt; x2 and y2 = &amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;);
  scanf (&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;%d %d&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt;x2, &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt;y2);
  printf (&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;Please enter Window coordinates &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;\n&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt; First enter XMax, YMax =&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;);
  scanf (&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;%d %d&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt;W_xmax, &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt;W_ymax);
  printf (&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;\n&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt; Now, enter XMin, YMin =&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;);
  scanf (&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;%d %d&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt;W_xmin, &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt;W_ymin);
  cleardevice ();
  delay (&lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;50&lt;/span&gt;);      
  &lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;//Window 
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;  rectangle (W_xmin, W_ymin, W_xmax, W_ymax);
  outtextxy (W_xmin, W_ymin &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;Window&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;);  
  &lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;//drawing a triangle 
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;  line (x, y, x1, y1);
  line (x1, y1, x2, y2);
  line (x2, y2, x, y);  
  &lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;// viewport 
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;  V_xmin &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;300&lt;/span&gt;;
  V_ymin &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;30&lt;/span&gt;;
  V_xmax &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;550&lt;/span&gt;;
  V_ymax &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;350&lt;/span&gt;;
  rectangle (V_xmin, V_ymin, V_xmax, V_ymax);
  outtextxy (V_xmin, V_ymin &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;Viewport&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;);  
  &lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;// calculatng Sx and Sy 
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;  sx &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; (&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;float&lt;/span&gt;) (V_xmax &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; V_xmin) &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; (W_xmax &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; W_xmin);
  sy &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; (&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;float&lt;/span&gt;) (V_ymax &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; V_ymin) &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; (W_ymax &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; W_ymin);
  x &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; V_xmin &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; (&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;float&lt;/span&gt;) ((x &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; W_xmin) &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; sx);
  x1 &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; V_xmin &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; (&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;float&lt;/span&gt;) ((x1 &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; W_xmin) &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; sx);
  x2 &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; V_xmin &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; (&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;float&lt;/span&gt;) ((x2 &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; W_xmin) &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; sx);
  y &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; V_ymin &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; (&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;float&lt;/span&gt;) ((y &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; W_ymin) &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; sy);
  y1 &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; V_ymin &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; (&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;float&lt;/span&gt;) ((y1 &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; W_ymin) &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; sy);
  y2 &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; V_ymin &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; (&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;float&lt;/span&gt;) ((y2 &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; W_ymin) &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; sy);
  &lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;// drawing triangle 
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;  line (x, y, x1, y1);
  line (x1, y1, x2, y2);
  line (x2, y2, x, y);
  getch ();
  closegraph ();
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h6 id=&#34;credits&#34;&gt;Credits&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to thank and mention some resources that I found particularly helpful in the writing of this post:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.javatpoint.com/computer-graphics-window-to-viewport-co-ordinate-transformation&#34;&gt;https://www.javatpoint.com/computer-graphics-window-to-viewport-co-ordinate-transformation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://programmerbay.com/program-to-implement-window-to-viewport-transformation/&#34;&gt;https://programmerbay.com/program-to-implement-window-to-viewport-transformation/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3_RA : LEARN THE ART AND PUT IT ASIDE</title>
      <link>https://lucarep.github.io/homework3/3_ra/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lucarep.github.io/homework3/3_ra/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents
 THE BASIC OF GDI+ THE GRAFIC OBJECT SIMPLE LINE DRAWINGS - Credits  THE BASIC OF GDI+ n graphical user interfaces such as Microsoft Windows, drawing on the screen is an important task.
Everything displayed on the screen is based on simple drawing operations. Often, environments such as Visual Basic abstract those drawing operations away from the developer. However, the same drawing operations still take place under the hood.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#the-basic-of-gdi&#34;&gt;THE BASIC OF GDI+&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#the-grafic-object&#34;&gt;THE GRAFIC OBJECT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#simple-line-drawings&#34;&gt;SIMPLE LINE DRAWINGS&lt;/a&gt;
- &lt;a href=&#34;#credits&#34;&gt;Credits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-basic-of-gdi&#34;&gt;THE BASIC OF GDI+&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;n graphical user interfaces such as Microsoft Windows, drawing on the screen is an important task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything displayed on the screen is based on simple drawing operations. Often, environments such as Visual Basic abstract those drawing operations away from the developer. However, the same drawing operations still take place under the hood. In Visual Studio .NET, developers have easy access to that drawing functionality whenever they need it through a technology called GDI+. Using GDI+, developers can easily perform drawing operations such as generating graphs or building custom controls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whenever you create a Windows Forms (WinForms) application .NET uses(and includes) GDI+ by default. The System.Drawing namespace contains all GDI+ functionality (as well as a few sub-namespaces). GDI+ provides all the basic drawing features, such as drawing lines, curves, circles, ellipses, strings, bitmaps, and more. GDI+ also gives developers the ability to fill areas with colors, patterns, and textures. This article will explain some of the basic drawing mechanisms that GDI+ provides.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-grafic-object&#34;&gt;THE GRAFIC OBJECT&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All GDI+ drawing is done using a Graphics object. This object has a large number of methods that encapsulate drawing operations on a drawing “canvas.” GDI+ supports a number of drawing canvases including: windows, bitmaps, and printer pages. Depending on the type of drawing canvas, the Graphics object is created or retrieved in a number of different ways. If you want to modify the contents of a bitmap file you would create a Bitmap canvas using the FromImage() method. This article will focus on one type of canvas: the window.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drawing in a WinForms-form is a somewhat peculiar task, because it is not enough to draw the graphic once. Instead, the “drawing” may have to be “refreshed” (re-drawn) whenever a window requires repainting. Repainting can happen whenever a user resizes a window or one window overlaps another window and then something brings the overlapped windows to the front.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So how do you know when to start drawing? The easiest way is to listen to the Paint event that is fired by every window (or control for that matter). The Paint event is a very good choice for drawing-logic because it fires whenever you need to refresh the display, and because part of the Paint event arguments (parameters) is a handle to the Graphics object. You can access the Graphics object via the following C# code:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-c#&#34; data-lang=&#34;c#&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;private&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;void&lt;/span&gt; Form1_Paint(&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;object&lt;/span&gt; sender,
System.Windows.Forms.PaintEventArgs e)
{
Graphics g = e.Graphics;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h1 id=&#34;simple-line-drawings&#34;&gt;SIMPLE LINE DRAWINGS&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A fundamental task performed by the graphics-object, is drawing lines and curves. You can use a number of methods for this purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In GDI+, unlike in regular (older) GDI, drawing lines and filling areas are two entirely different operations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you draw lines, you must consider a number of fundamental things. For example, you need to choose what kind of line to draw.. Do you want a straight line, or a curve? Do you want a simple, single line, or do you want to draw a complex line composed out of many segments? Maybe you want to draw a closed shape that forms a completely enclosed area with an identical start and end point (such as a circle, rectangle, or polygon)? Depending on the desired shape of the line, different methods are available to generate them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Less obvious than the position and shape of the line, are the parameters for a line. You might ask, “What parameters can I specify for a line?” You can specify the following parameters: attributes such as color and thickness, start and end-points, and the shape of the end of a line such as whether the line ends in a rounded or square “head” or ends in an arrow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In GDI+, lines are represented by Pen objects. Pens encapsulate all the attributes described above. GDI+ provides a number of default Pen objects, such as pens of different colors. The following code demonstrated drawing a simple straight line using different pens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-c#&#34; data-lang=&#34;c#&#34;&gt;g.DrawLine(Pens.Red,&lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;,&lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;,&lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;200&lt;/span&gt;,&lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;100&lt;/span&gt;)
g.DrawLine(Pens.Green,&lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;,&lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;30&lt;/span&gt;,&lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;200&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;120&lt;/span&gt;)
g.DrawLine(Pens.Blue,&lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;,&lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;50&lt;/span&gt;,&lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;200&lt;/span&gt;,&lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;140&lt;/span&gt;)

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you want to adjust the thickness of the used pen, you need to instantiate a custom pen object. This example generates a 5-pixel thick red pen and uses it to draw another line:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-c#&#34; data-lang=&#34;c#&#34;&gt;g.DrawLine( &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;_&lt;/span&gt;   New Pen(Color.Red, &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;5&lt;/span&gt;), &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;_&lt;/span&gt;   &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;100&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;200&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;190&lt;/span&gt;)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you play with the DrawLine() method a bit, you will discover that it has a large number of overloads, though the result of these overloads is the same. You can just take different paths to your destination. I encourage you to experiment with the different options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For instance, you can draw circles and ellipses:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-c#&#34; data-lang=&#34;c#&#34;&gt;g.DrawEllipse(Pens.Red, &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;_&lt;/span&gt;   &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;150&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;80&lt;/span&gt;)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Similarly, you can draw rectangles with this code:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-c#&#34; data-lang=&#34;c#&#34;&gt;g.DrawRectangle(Pens.Green, &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;_&lt;/span&gt;   &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;20&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;100&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;120&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;60&lt;/span&gt;)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h6 id=&#34;credits&#34;&gt;Credits&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to thank and mention some resources that I found particularly helpful in the writing of this post:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.codemag.com/article/0305031&#34;&gt;https://www.codemag.com/article/0305031&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4_R</title>
      <link>https://lucarep.github.io/homework3/4_r/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lucarep.github.io/homework3/4_r/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents
 INTRO WHAT ARE MARGINAL DISTRIBUTION? WHAT ARE JOINT FREQUENCY? WHAT ARE CONDITIONAL DISTRIBUTION? BAYES THEOREM: WHAT IS STATISTICAL INDEPENDENCE?  Note - Credits    INTRO in this post we will talk about what are marginal, joint and conditional distributions. later we will discuss how to use Bayes&#39; theorem using relative frequencies. Finally, we will explain the concept of statistical independence and why, in case of independence, the relative joint frequencies are equal to the products of the corresponding marginal frequencies.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#intro&#34;&gt;INTRO&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#what-are-marginal-distribution&#34;&gt;WHAT ARE MARGINAL DISTRIBUTION?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#what-are-joint-frequency&#34;&gt;WHAT ARE JOINT FREQUENCY?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#what-are-conditional-distribution&#34;&gt;WHAT ARE CONDITIONAL DISTRIBUTION?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#bayes-theorem&#34;&gt;BAYES THEOREM:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#what-is-statistical-independence&#34;&gt;WHAT IS STATISTICAL INDEPENDENCE?&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#note&#34;&gt;Note&lt;/a&gt;
- &lt;a href=&#34;#credits&#34;&gt;Credits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;INTRO&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in this post we will talk about what are marginal, joint and conditional distributions. later we will discuss how to use Bayes&#39; theorem using relative frequencies. Finally, we will explain the concept of statistical independence and why, in case of independence, the relative joint frequencies are equal to the products of the corresponding marginal frequencies. So, let&amp;rsquo;s get started!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-are-marginal-distribution&#34;&gt;WHAT ARE MARGINAL DISTRIBUTION?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The frequency of an category occurring (Freq(X)), it may be thought of as an &lt;strong&gt;unconditional frequency.&lt;/strong&gt;  It is not conditioned on another category.  Example:  the frequency that a card drawn is red (Freq(red) = 0.5).  Another example could be:  the frequency that a card drawn is a 4  (Freq(four)=1/13).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$$ Freq(X) = \frac{\text{count of statistical units that fall into category X}}{\text{total count of statistical units}}$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-are-joint-frequency&#34;&gt;WHAT ARE JOINT FREQUENCY?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Example:  the frequency that a card is a four and red =Freq(four and red) = 2/52=1/26.  (There are two red fours in a deck of 52, the 4 of hearts and the 4 of diamonds).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$$ Freq(X \cap Y) = \frac{\text{counts of statistical units falling into categories X and Y}}{\text{total count of statistical units}}$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-are-conditional-distribution&#34;&gt;WHAT ARE CONDITIONAL DISTRIBUTION?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Freq(X | Y) is the frequency of a statistical units falling into category X, given that it already falls into category Y. Example:  given that you drew a red card, what’s the frequency that it’s a four (Freq(four|red))=2/26=1/13.  So out of the 26 red cards (given a red card), there are two fours so 2/26=1/13.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$$ Freq(X|Y) = \frac{Freq(X \cap Y)}{Freq(Y)}$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;bayes-theorem&#34;&gt;BAYES THEOREM:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bayes’ theorem is an equation that allows us to manipulate conditional frequencies. For two categories, X and Y, Bayes’ theorem lets us to go from Freq(Y|X) to Freq(X|Y) if we know the marginal probabilities of the outcomes of Xand the frequency of Y, given the outcomes of X. Here is the equation for Bayes’ theorem for two categorys with two possible outcome (X and not Y). Note the inter-steps that show how the final result is reached.
It follows just from the conditional distribution equation, where we substitute 
Freq(X ∩Y) with Freq(Y|X)Freq(X).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$$ Freq(X|Y) = \frac{Freq(X \cap Y)}{Freq(Y)} = \frac{Freq(Y|X)Freq(X)}{Freq(Y)}$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-is-statistical-independence&#34;&gt;WHAT IS STATISTICAL INDEPENDENCE?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$$ Pr(A|B) = Pr(A)$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;we can say that A, is statistically independent of B when :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;whether B happens makes no difference to how often A happens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If this holds, though, then B is also independent of A :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$$ Pr(B|A) = \frac{Pr(A \cap B)}{Pr(A)} = \frac{Pr(A)Pr(B)}{Pr(A)} = Pr(B)$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;so we can just say “A and B are independent”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;note&#34;&gt;Note&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Statistically independent is not the same as mutually exclusive: if A and B are mutually exclusive, then they can’t be independent, unless one of them is probability 0 to start with: 
$$ Pr(A \cap B) = 0 = Pr(A)Pr(B)$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&#34;credits&#34;&gt;Credits&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to thank and mention some resources that I found particularly helpful in the writing of this post:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sites.nicholas.duke.edu/statsreview/jmc/&#34;&gt;https://sites.nicholas.duke.edu/statsreview/jmc/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.stat.cmu.edu/~cshalizi/36-220/lecture-5.pdf&#34;&gt;https://www.stat.cmu.edu/~cshalizi/36-220/lecture-5.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2_RA : 50 SHADES OF DATA</title>
      <link>https://lucarep.github.io/homework3/2_ra/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lucarep.github.io/homework3/2_ra/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents
 WHAT IS DATA VISUALIZATION? IS IT IMPORTANT TO CHOOSE A SPECIFIC TYPE OF CHART TO VISUALIZE DATA?  BUT WHY? INFORM COMPARE CHANGE ORGANIZE RELATIONSHIPS - Credits    WHAT IS DATA VISUALIZATION? The human mind is very receptive to visual information. That’s why data visualization is a powerful tool for communication.
Data visualization is the visual presentation of data or information. The goal of data visualization is to communicate data or information clearly and effectively to readers.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#what-is-data-visualization&#34;&gt;WHAT IS DATA VISUALIZATION?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#is-it-important-to-choose-a-specific-type-of-chart-to-visualize-data&#34;&gt;IS IT IMPORTANT TO CHOOSE A SPECIFIC TYPE OF CHART TO VISUALIZE DATA?&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#but-why&#34;&gt;BUT WHY?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#inform&#34;&gt;INFORM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#compare&#34;&gt;COMPARE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#change&#34;&gt;CHANGE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#organize&#34;&gt;ORGANIZE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#relationships&#34;&gt;RELATIONSHIPS&lt;/a&gt;
- &lt;a href=&#34;#credits&#34;&gt;Credits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-is-data-visualization&#34;&gt;WHAT IS DATA VISUALIZATION?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The human mind is very receptive to visual information. That’s why data visualization is a powerful tool for communication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data visualization is the visual presentation of data or information. The goal of data visualization is to communicate data or information clearly and effectively to readers. Typically, data is visualized in the form of a chart, infographic, diagram or map. Charts use visual symbols like line, bars, dots, slices, and icons to represent data points.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;is-it-important-to-choose-a-specific-type-of-chart-to-visualize-data&#34;&gt;IS IT IMPORTANT TO CHOOSE A SPECIFIC TYPE OF CHART TO VISUALIZE DATA?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Short answer: &lt;strong&gt;yes&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;but-why&#34;&gt;BUT WHY?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, we can say that some charts are better suited for some purposes than others and help us to better communicate what we want, let&amp;rsquo;s see some examples:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;inform&#34;&gt;INFORM&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You want to convey a single important data point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Single big number&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Donut chart&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pictograph&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;compare&#34;&gt;COMPARE&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You want to compare categories or show composition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bar chart&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bubble chart&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pie chart&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stacked bar chart&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bubble cloud&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Treemap&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Word Cloud&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;change&#34;&gt;CHANGE&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You want to show change over time by location.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Line chart&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Area chart&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Timeline&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Map chart&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;organize&#34;&gt;ORGANIZE&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You want to show groupings,rankings, or process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;List&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flow chart&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Venn diagram&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mind map&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pyramid&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Table&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;relationships&#34;&gt;RELATIONSHIPS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You want to reveal relationships correlations or distributions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scatter plot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Histogram&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multi-Series chart&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&#34;credits&#34;&gt;Credits&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to thank and mention some resources that I found particularly helpful in the writing of this post:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://venngage.com/blog/data-visualization/&#34;&gt;https://venngage.com/blog/data-visualization/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1_RA : Floating point representation</title>
      <link>https://lucarep.github.io/homework2/1_ra/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lucarep.github.io/homework2/1_ra/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents
 Rounding Errors Rounding Modes - Credits  Rounding Errors Because floating-point numbers have a limited number of digits, they cannot represent all real numbers accurately: when there are more digits than the format allows, the leftover ones are omitted – the number is rounded. There are three reasons why this can be necessary:
  Too many significant digits – The great advantage of floating point is that leading and trailing zeroes (within the range provided by the exponent) don’t need to be stored.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#rounding-errors&#34;&gt;Rounding Errors&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#rounding-modes&#34;&gt;Rounding Modes&lt;/a&gt;
- &lt;a href=&#34;#credits&#34;&gt;Credits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;rounding-errors&#34;&gt;Rounding Errors&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because floating-point numbers have a limited number of digits, they cannot represent all real numbers accurately: when there are more digits than the format allows, the leftover ones are omitted – the number is rounded. There are three reasons why this can be necessary:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Too many significant digits – The great advantage of floating point is that leading and trailing zeroes (within the range provided by the exponent) don’t need to be stored. But if, without those, there are still more digits than the significand can store, rounding becomes necessary. In other words, if your number simply requires more precision than the format can provide, you’ll have to sacrifice some of it, which is no big surprise. For example, with a floating point format that has 3 digits in the significand, 1000 does not require rounding, and neither does 10000 or 1110 – but 1001 will have to be rounded. With the large number of significand digits available in typical floating-point formats, this may seem to be a rarely encountered problem, but if you perform a sequence of calculations, especially multiplication and division, you can very quickly reach this point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Periodical digits – Any (irreducible) fraction where the denominator has a prime factor that does not occur in the base requires an infinite number of digits that repeat periodically after a certain point, and this can already happen for very simple fractions. For example, in decimal 1/4, 3/5 and 8/20 are finite, because 2 and 5 are the prime factors of 10. But 1/3 is not finite, nor is 2/3 or 1/7 or 5/6, because 3 and 7 are not factors of 10. Fractions with a prime factor of 5 in the denominator can be finite in base 10, but not in base 2 – the biggest source of confusion for most novice users of floating-point numbers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Non-rational numbers – Non-rational numbers cannot be represented as a regular fraction at all, and in positional notation (no matter what base) they require an infinite number of non-recurring digits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;rounding-modes&#34;&gt;Rounding Modes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are different methods to do rounding, and this can be very important in programming, because rounding can cause different problems in various contexts that can be addressed by using a better rounding mode. The most common rounding modes are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rounding towards zero – simply truncate the extra digits. The simplest method, but it introduces larger errors than necessary as well as a bias towards zero when dealing with mainly positive or mainly negative numbers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rounding half away from zero – if the truncated fraction is greater than or equal to half the base, increase the last remaining digit. This is the method generally taught in school and used by most people. It minimizes errors, but also introduces a bias (away from zero).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rounding half to even also known as banker’s rounding – if the truncated fraction is greater than half the base, increase the last remaining digit. If it is equal to half the base, increase the digit only if that produces an even result. This minimizes errors and bias, and is therefore preferred for bookkeeping.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;Towards zero&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;Half Away from zero&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;Half to even&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-1.6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;-1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;-2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;-2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2.6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2.5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-2.4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;-2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;-2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;-2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&#34;credits&#34;&gt;Credits&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to thank and mention some resources that I found particularly helpful in the writing of this post:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://floating-point-gui.de/basic/&#34;&gt;https://floating-point-gui.de/basic/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://floating-point-gui.de/errors/rounding/&#34;&gt;https://floating-point-gui.de/errors/rounding/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3_R : ONLINE ALGORITHM</title>
      <link>https://lucarep.github.io/homework2/3_r/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lucarep.github.io/homework2/3_r/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents
 WHAT IS AN ONLINE ALGORITHM? HOW WE CAN OBTAIN AN ONLINE ALGO FOR THE ARITHMETIC MEAN:  KAHAN SUMMATION ALGORITHM:   WHY IS AN ONLINE ALGO BETTER IN THIS CASE? - Credits  WHAT IS AN ONLINE ALGORITHM? Citing Wikipedia:
 In computer science, an online algorithm is one that can process its input piece-by-piece in a serial fashion, i.e., in the order that the input is fed to the algorithm, without having the entire input available from the start.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#what-is-an-online-algorithm&#34;&gt;WHAT IS AN ONLINE ALGORITHM?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#how-we-can-obtain-an-online-algo-for-the-arithmetic-mean&#34;&gt;HOW WE CAN OBTAIN AN ONLINE ALGO FOR THE ARITHMETIC MEAN:&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#kahan-summation-algorithm&#34;&gt;KAHAN SUMMATION ALGORITHM:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#why-is-an-online-algo-better-in-this-case&#34;&gt;WHY IS AN ONLINE ALGO BETTER IN THIS CASE?&lt;/a&gt;
- &lt;a href=&#34;#credits&#34;&gt;Credits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-is-an-online-algorithm&#34;&gt;WHAT IS AN ONLINE ALGORITHM?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Citing &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Online_algorithm&#34;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In computer science, an online algorithm is one that can process its input piece-by-piece in a serial fashion, i.e., in the order that the input is fed to the algorithm, without having the entire input available from the start. In contrast, an offline algorithm is given the whole problem data from the beginning and is required to output an answer which solves the problem at hand. (For example, selection sort requires that the entire list be given before it can sort it, while insertion sort doesn&amp;rsquo;t.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can then summarize this definition by saying:
an online algorithm takes as input a &lt;strong&gt;stream&lt;/strong&gt; of continuous data, while an offline algorithm attempts to solve the problem by already having all the data available from the first moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-we-can-obtain-an-online-algo-for-the-arithmetic-mean&#34;&gt;HOW WE CAN OBTAIN AN ONLINE ALGO FOR THE ARITHMETIC MEAN:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem of calculating the average is trivial, most of us since elementary school can solve it, however solving it with an online algorithm is a more complex task.
Here, comes in help &lt;strong&gt;DONALD KNUTH&lt;/strong&gt; ,an American computer scientist, mathematician, and professor emeritus at Stanford University, in his book ‘&lt;strong&gt;The Art of Computer Programming&lt;/strong&gt;’ wrote an alternative formula to compute the online mean for &lt;strong&gt;huge data-stream.&lt;/strong&gt; The following is the mathematical formula he found to solve the problem:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.codecogs.com/eqnedit.php?latex=x_{n}&amp;space;=&amp;space;\frac{x_{n&amp;space;-1}(n&amp;space;-1)&amp;space;&amp;plus;&amp;space;x_{n}}{n}&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://latex.codecogs.com/gif.latex?x_{n}&amp;space;=&amp;space;\frac{x_{n&amp;space;-1}(n&amp;space;-1)&amp;space;&amp;plus;&amp;space;x_{n}}{n}&#34; title=&#34;x_{n} = \frac{x_{n -1}(n -1) + x_{n}}{n}&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;kahan-summation-algorithm&#34;&gt;KAHAN SUMMATION ALGORITHM:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A code version of the algorithm, is the following one introduced by &lt;strong&gt;KAHAN&lt;/strong&gt;, which is designed to minimize errors, this is done by keeping a separate running compensation (a variable that accumulates small errors).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-js&#34; data-lang=&#34;js&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;KahanSum&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;input&lt;/span&gt;)
    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;sum&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;0.0&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;c&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;0.0&lt;/span&gt;                 &lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;// A running compensation for lost low-order bits.
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;i&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;to&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;input&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;length&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;do&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;y&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;input&lt;/span&gt;[&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;i&lt;/span&gt;] &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;c&lt;/span&gt;    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;// So far, so good: c is zero.
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;        &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;t&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;sum&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;y&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;// Alas, sum is big, y small, so low-order digits of y are lost.
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;        &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;c&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; (&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;t&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;sum&lt;/span&gt;) &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;y&lt;/span&gt;       &lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;// (t - sum) cancels the high-order part of y; subtracting y recovers negative (low part of y)
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;        &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;sum&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;t&lt;/span&gt;                 &lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;// Algebraically, c should always be zero. Beware overly-aggressive optimizing compilers!
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;next&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;i&lt;/span&gt;                      &lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;// Next time around, the lost low part will be added to y in a fresh attempt.
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;sum&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h1 id=&#34;why-is-an-online-algo-better-in-this-case&#34;&gt;WHY IS AN ONLINE ALGO BETTER IN THIS CASE?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the answer to the question starts with one word &lt;strong&gt;digitalization&lt;/strong&gt;.
We live in an increasingly connected world, where more and more applications are entrusted to &lt;strong&gt;computers&lt;/strong&gt;, so it is unthinkable to be able to store a large amount of data in RAM or hard drive and then use them later, because they take up a lot of &lt;strong&gt;space and resources&lt;/strong&gt;. That&amp;rsquo;s why we need something more efficient, so over the years the &lt;strong&gt;online&lt;/strong&gt; approach has gained more and more attention, because it allows us to save precious resources. Of course, &lt;strong&gt;it&amp;rsquo;s not all gold that glitters&lt;/strong&gt;, in fact, for problems that don&amp;rsquo;t require large amounts of data, an offline approach is preferable because it&amp;rsquo;s easier to implement and in some cases may even be more efficient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&#34;credits&#34;&gt;Credits&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to thank and mention some resources that I found particularly helpful in the writing of this post:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Federica Sole, &lt;a href=&#34;https://statisticsforcs.wordpress.com/2017/10/24/best-algorithms-to-compute-the-online-data-stream-arithmetic-mean/&#34;&gt;Best algorithms to compute the “online data stream” arithmetic mean&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2_R : LET&#39;S TALK ABOUT DATA</title>
      <link>https://lucarep.github.io/homework2/2_r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lucarep.github.io/homework2/2_r/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents
 What is a Database? The Data Warehouse : What is a Data Mart? OLAP and OLTP : two useful tools Definition of OLAP: Definition of OLTP: OLAP vs OLTP: - Credits  What is a Database? Our discussion of data starts here, the database, but what is actually a database? Citing Oracle:
 A database is an organized collection of structured information, or data, typically stored electronically in a computer system.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#what-is-a-database&#34;&gt;What is a Database?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#the-data-warehouse-&#34;&gt;The Data Warehouse :&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#what-is-a-data-mart&#34;&gt;What is a Data Mart?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#olap-and-oltp--two-useful-tools&#34;&gt;OLAP and OLTP : two useful tools&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#definition-of-olap&#34;&gt;Definition of OLAP:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#definition-of-oltp&#34;&gt;Definition of OLTP:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#olap-vs-oltp&#34;&gt;OLAP vs OLTP:&lt;/a&gt;
- &lt;a href=&#34;#credits&#34;&gt;Credits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-is-a-database&#34;&gt;What is a Database?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our discussion of data starts here, the database, but what is actually a database?
Citing &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.oracle.com/database/what-is-database/&#34;&gt;Oracle&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A database is an &lt;strong&gt;organized collection of structured information&lt;/strong&gt;, or data, typically stored electronically in a &lt;strong&gt;computer system&lt;/strong&gt;. A database is usually controlled by a database management system (&lt;strong&gt;DBMS&lt;/strong&gt;). Together, the data and the DBMS, along with the applications that are associated with them, are referred to as a database system, often shortened to just database.Data within the most common types of databases in operation today is typically modeled in &lt;strong&gt;rows and columns&lt;/strong&gt; in a series of &lt;strong&gt;tables&lt;/strong&gt; to make processing and data querying efficient. The data can then be easily accessed, managed, modified, updated, controlled, and organized. Most databases use structured query language (&lt;strong&gt;SQL&lt;/strong&gt;) for writing and querying data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;so, now that we know what it takes to allow us to record data, we can better address how it is handled in the real world for different purposes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-data-warehouse-&#34;&gt;The Data Warehouse :&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First of all, a &lt;strong&gt;data warehouse&lt;/strong&gt; is a particular type of &lt;strong&gt;database&lt;/strong&gt;, but there is a major difference:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a database is built to &lt;strong&gt;record&lt;/strong&gt; the data provided to it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a Data Warehouse is designed to perform data &lt;strong&gt;aggregations&lt;/strong&gt; for analytical purposes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other words, databases are a mathematical basis for collecting data and querying them for operational purposes. The data warehouse, on the other hand, is an analytical system of data that has strategic purposes in the &lt;strong&gt;planning of business processes&lt;/strong&gt;. In addition, data warehouses are very important in data mining, artificial intelligence (AI), and machine learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-is-a-data-mart&#34;&gt;What is a Data Mart?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can see the &lt;strong&gt;data mart&lt;/strong&gt; as a focused version of a &lt;strong&gt;data warehouse&lt;/strong&gt; described above. Specifically, citing &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ibm.com/cloud/learn/data-mart&#34;&gt;IBM&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A data mart is a subset of a data warehouse focused on a particular line of business, department, or subject area. Data marts make specific data available to a defined group of users, which allows those users to &lt;strong&gt;quickly&lt;/strong&gt; access critical insights without wasting time searching through an entire data warehouse. For example, many companies may have a data mart that aligns with a specific department in the business, such as finance, sales, or marketing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, different data marts may exist depending on the areas of study we are interested in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;olap-and-oltp--two-useful-tools&#34;&gt;OLAP and OLTP : two useful tools&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We could conceptually summarize what OLAP and OLTP are with a &lt;strong&gt;simple question&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;in the case of OLAP we would ask &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;what will happen?&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;in the case of OLTP we would ask &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;what is happening?&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;definition-of-olap&#34;&gt;Definition of OLAP:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OLAP stands for: 
&lt;strong&gt;On-Line Analytical Processsing&lt;/strong&gt;.
We can see it as a set of &lt;strong&gt;software&lt;/strong&gt; techniques that allows to analyze a large amount of collected data and it is the basic technology of &lt;strong&gt;data warehouse&lt;/strong&gt;. Companies use it to &lt;strong&gt;predict&lt;/strong&gt; sales results, cost trends, results of marketing and communication campaigns, organize survey data and other similar cases. We can therefore summarize everything in the fact that the OLAP analysis system is one of the tools that can allow you to make &lt;strong&gt;business decisions&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;definition-of-oltp&#34;&gt;Definition of OLTP:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OLTP stands for:
&lt;strong&gt;On-Line Transaction Processsing&lt;/strong&gt;.
we can see it as a set of &lt;strong&gt;software&lt;/strong&gt; techniques that are
used to manage &lt;strong&gt;transaction-oriented&lt;/strong&gt; applications. It is popular in financial transactions, retail sales, and customer relationship management (CRM). Booking airline tickets online, online banking, online shopping are practical examples of systems based on the use of OLTP. OLTP is used to &lt;strong&gt;record&lt;/strong&gt; insertion, &lt;strong&gt;update&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;deletion&lt;/strong&gt; of data during a transaction. So, as you can imagine these operations in order to ensure reliability must be &lt;strong&gt;atomic&lt;/strong&gt;. Also, OLTP queries are simpler and shorter and thus require less time in processing and less storage space. A key aspect is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;we can see OLTP as the data source for OLAP.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;olap-vs-oltp&#34;&gt;OLAP vs OLTP:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OLAP tools differ from OLTPs in that the former aim to find and achieve queries that are as complex as possible; the latter, on the other hand, aim to ensure integrity and security of transactions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below is a list of other substantial differences between the two:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OLTP is an online transaction system instead OLAP is an online data retrieval and analysis system;
online transaction data is the data source for OLTP;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OLTP&amp;rsquo;s main operations are inserting, updating and deleting data while OLAP&amp;rsquo;s main operation is extracting complex data for later analysis;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OLAP has a long and less frequent transaction while OLTP has short but frequent transactions;
OLTP&amp;rsquo;s response times are much faster than OLAP as it deals with short transactions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OLAP queries are very complex compared to OLTP, as they deal with a much larger amount of data and are also more structured.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OLAP databases are not changed frequently, so data integrity is not affected. OLTP databases, on the other hand, are changed frequently, so it is important to maintain data integrity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OLAP is used for planning and decision making while OLTP is used for controlling and executing key business activities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&#34;credits&#34;&gt;Credits&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to thank and mention some resources that I found particularly helpful in the writing of this post:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bucap.it/news/approfondimenti-tematici/gestione-del-magazzino/database-data-warehouse-principali-differenze.htm#:~:text=Il%20primo%20obiettivo%20del%20database,di%20dati%20a%20fini%20analitici.&#34;&gt;Difference between database and data warehouse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.businessintelligencegroup.it/olap-e-oltp-cosa-sono-e-quali-sono-le-principali-differenze/&#34;&gt;OLAP e OLTP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1_R : LET&#39;S TALK ABOUT STATISTICS</title>
      <link>https://lucarep.github.io/homework1/1_r/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lucarep.github.io/homework1/1_r/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents
 What is statistics? 📊 Is statistics a science, a branch of mathematics or both? 🤔 - Also, what defines a scientific field? - Credits  What is statistics? 📊  &amp;ldquo;If a 30 year old man has his head in an oven and his feet in ice, a statistician would say that on average he feels fine.&amp;rdquo;
 There are tons of data out there and all those numbers alone don&amp;rsquo;t make much sense, this is where the statistics comes in, in statistics we carry out analysis, interpretation, organization and presentation of this data, so informed decision can be made.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#what-is-statistics-&#34;&gt;What is statistics? 📊&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#is-statistics-a-science-a-branch-of-mathematics-or-both-&#34;&gt;Is statistics a science, a branch of mathematics or both? 🤔&lt;/a&gt;
- &lt;a href=&#34;#also-what-defines-a-scientific-field&#34;&gt;Also, what defines a scientific field?&lt;/a&gt;
- &lt;a href=&#34;#credits&#34;&gt;Credits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-is-statistics-&#34;&gt;What is statistics? 📊&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;If a 30 year old man has his head in an oven and his feet in ice, a statistician would say that on average he feels fine.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are tons of data out there and all those numbers alone don&amp;rsquo;t make much sense, this is where the statistics comes in, in statistics we carry out &lt;strong&gt;analysis, interpretation, organization and presentation of this data&lt;/strong&gt;, so informed decision can be made. A trivial example that we can observe every day are the weather forecasts, to make this forecasts statisticians create computer models based on previous weather reports. But statistics is literally &lt;strong&gt;everywhere&lt;/strong&gt;, here&amp;rsquo;s an example of some of the sectors that use it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pharmaceutical Industry&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Food Industry&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plants&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Designer Brands&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Computers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Insurance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Medicine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, in this historical moment we all know unfortunately that there&amp;rsquo;s a pandemic of &lt;strong&gt;Covid-19&lt;/strong&gt; in progress, even here the statistics play a &lt;strong&gt;key role&lt;/strong&gt;, as you can make estimates of how many contagions there may be in the future, given the current contagions. Take &lt;strong&gt;Covid vaccines&lt;/strong&gt; also as an example, did you know that pharmaceutical companies like &lt;strong&gt;Pfizer&lt;/strong&gt; employ many statisticians? Here they analyze the results conducted in preclinical research and clinical trials,
to help then develop a vaccine that is &lt;strong&gt;safe and effective&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;is-statistics-a-science-a-branch-of-mathematics-or-both-&#34;&gt;Is statistics a science, a branch of mathematics or both? 🤔&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can summarize the above with a quote from American Statistical Association:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Statistics is the science of learning from data, and of measuring, controlling and communicating &lt;strong&gt;uncertainty&lt;/strong&gt;.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;also, John Turkey (author of Exploratory Dat Analysis) said:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Statistics is a science, not a branch of mathematics, but it uses mathematical models as essential tools.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s the difference?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The primary difference between the two is &lt;strong&gt;uncertainty&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider two problems:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How far is it to work in miles?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How far is it to work in minutes?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first problem is a math problem because, assuming you take the same route, the answer is fixed. The second problem is a statistical problem because you will not always get the same answer due to weather or traffic conditions, how many lights you get stuck at etc., there is a level of uncertainty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now in order to understand statistics you do need to know probability which is a branch of mathematics (The study of finite measures that a normalized to 1). But probability is not statistics anymore than algebra is physics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&#34;also-what-defines-a-scientific-field&#34;&gt;Also, what defines a scientific field?&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every field of scientific inquiry is defined by &lt;strong&gt;three things&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What it studies: Statistics is the study of uncertainty. More specifically, it is the science of probability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why it studies the What: The outcomes of any and every natural process vary in random, yet understandable, ways (i.e. Natural Variation). Statistics examines and specifies these patterns of randomness. By understanding natural variation, we are able to identify occurrences of unnatural variation and seek their underlying cause.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How it studies the What: Like many sciences, mathematics is the formal language of statistics. However, it is not its only tool. Statistics also uses computers for both simulation and analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, many people view statistics as a branch of mathematics, in many ways this is true, because its origins lie within mathematics. However, it have evolved past that and is its own independent field of inquiry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&#34;credits&#34;&gt;Credits&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to thank and mention some resources that I found particularly helpful in the writing of this post:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aveea : What is Statistics? (and what can you do with it) 
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/M6MKQ88LpFA&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kenneth Ganning (Ph.D Statistics), Thom Flottemesch (Ph.D Statistics) :  &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.quora.com/What-is-statistics-a-science-of&#34;&gt;What is statistics a science of?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
